in this video I'm going to show you a
better way to clean your max
keyboard how's it going folks this is
Jeff Benjamin with 9o5 Mac we've all
been there before we're eating at our
desk and we have just stuff all over
crumbs whatever the case may be all over
your keyboard you want to clean it off
or maybe even your cat decides to take a
nap right on your keyboard and they get
paw prints all over the keyboard's keys
now of course we know how to clean
keyboard it's not really that difficult
just take a cloth and wipe it off right
but when you do that with your Mac own
then you start to hit Keys you maybe
input text that's erroneous you just
maybe even quit a program that you're
working on at the moment it's not a good
thing right A Better Way is to use an
app called keyboard cleaner and this is
a free app it was actually submitted to
the Mac App Store a long time ago but
Apple never approved it for whatever
reason but this app basically allows you
to suspend the activity on your Mac it
goes to a black screen so that you can't
input text while you're cleaning your
keyboard so I'm just going to launch the
app just like that and now keyboard
cleaner is launched it's a black screen
and now I can clean my keyboard at will
without worrying about inputting text or
quitting an app or anything like that
just messing up something I'm working on
I don't have to go and shut down my Mac
completely once I'm finished all I need
to do is hold the command key and press
the Q button to quit the application and
now I'm back to my Mac like normal with
a clean keyboard so ladies and gentlemen
let me know what you think about
keyboard cleaner Down Below in the
comment section this is Jeff with 95
Mac