another chance for Katie
[Applause]
static palter tries to go for the back
corner but Albright was there and then
fecky with another
swing Conor Dives and puts it
over rally will
continue Burks into the
block roll shot from Joselyn Burks
Becky tries to end the rally donelly the
day again donelly Dives for that ball
and keeps it in play longest rally we've
seen so far Hunter out to
FY static into the block play
continues donelly saves it will this
rally end who's going to take
it hun the back set rolson puts it
[Applause]
over Hunter goes for her own attack but
Burks was ready FY big swing from her if
be Al lot will have the point on the
attack
air
wow well you don't see that very often
we're going to see a replay here I'm not
quite sure how much we're going to see
cuz this was one of the longest rallies
I think I've ever seen in volleyball to
be quite honest with you great defensive
plays you're seeing incredible stamina
nice grit and then the hitting air and
you can see Nebraska's uh one of
Nebraska's players almost collapsed she
was so so exhausted