about 1.7 million americans earn at or
below the federal minimum wage
that's seven dollars and 25 cents per
hour which works out to about 15 000
a year even though the cost of living
continues to rise
this number has stayed the same for over
a decade
minimum wage is the lowest amount an
employer can legally pay an hourly
worker
but there are some exceptions for
example according to federal law
workers who receive tips like waiters
and bartenders employers only have to
pay them two dollars and thirteen cents
an hour
disabled workers can earn as little as
one dollar an hour
but many states have their own laws for
example 29 states
plus washington dc have a higher minimum
wage you'll always get the highest wage
possible
so in states with no minimum wage or a
lower one the federal minimum applies
this amount hasn't changed since july
the longest period in history without a
raise when president franklin d
roosevelt first introduced the federal
minimum wage
he said it was meant to be the wages of
a decent living
in 1938 that was established at 25 cents
an hour
since then it's been raised 22 times but
after 1968 it just couldn't keep up with
inflation
so in 2019 seven dollars and 25 cents
was actually only worth six dollars
people have been pushing for an increase
in minimum wage for years
but there's long been debate about how
that would affect the overall economy
one side says if workers are paid more
employers will hire fewer of them
leading to greater unemployment they
also argue that it would cut into the
employer's profits
and increase inflation the other side
says higher pay
would reduce employee turnover increase
consumer spending
and help people keep up with the rising
cost of living
hey thanks for watching if you like this
video check out these other videos from
usa today to stay up to date with all
the latest news