whether it's a football team broadway
production
factory line or fire department each
person has their defined roles
the same is true in court of course
everyone from the bailiff to the court
reporter
has a job to do but the judge and the
jury
are the most crucial roles in court if
you find yourself in a jury trial
at the very least you should know what
the roles of the judge and the jury are
although you undoubtedly have the gist
certainty
usually wins the day in the courtroom so
let's break down the role of the judge
first
even in a jury trial the judge still
wears many hats
metaphorical hats of course first and
foremost
the judge is an independent impartial
decision maker in the pursuit of justice
each side makes its arguments and
presents the facts and evidence that it
wants the jury to consider
it's up to the judge to oversee it all
without bias
the judge is the ruler of the courtroom
she decides all matters of courtroom
procedure
she also decides all legal issues
including ruling on evidentiary
objections
when the judge sustains an objection to
evidence it means she agrees with the
party objecting and the evidence or
testimony is disallowed
if she overrules the objection it means
she disagrees with the party objecting
and the evidence will come in sometimes
some evidence questions are settled
beforehand
to the judge's decisions on pre-trial
motions but often the evidentiary issues
cannot be predicted in advance
and must be ruled on during the trial
another part of the judge's duty is to
act as a guide for the jury
the judge will instruct the jury about
the law before the jury's verdict
so that they make the most informed
decision possible juries are assembled
to determine if someone is liable or not
liable in a case
based on the evidence that has been
admitted and only on that evidence
this makes the jury in stuffy lawyer
speak the trier of fact
if the jury does find the defendant
liable they must also decide how much in
damages the defendant must pay
there are cases where a jury is not
permitted or where the parties have
waived a trial by jury
the judge plays both the normal role of
a judge but is also
the trier of fact the judge decides both
the legal issues
and the factual issues this can be more
streamlined and efficient
but it also has its drawbacks for one
the decision is being made by
one person not six it also presents the
problem that the judge may rule certain
evidence inadmissible
but unlike a jury the judge has already
seen the evidence that the trier effect
should not see
the law presumes that the judge has the
ability that jurors do not
to resist the temptation of being
influenced by inadmissible evidence
by the way trying the case without a
jury is called a bench trial
it's called that because confusingly
enough the elevated desk the judge sits
behind
is not called a desk or a table but a
bench
even more confusingly the judge sits on
a chair
not a bench but the word comes from the
days when judges
actually sat on benches anyway you could
say that in a bench trial the only one
getting benched
is the jury don't let yourself get
sidelined by a lack of knowledge on how
the game is played
to take a tour of the courtroom and see
what goes on when a trial is taking
place
as you can see there are several people
in the court
not only the judge and the attorneys but
there are several
other people who are involved in the
process of conducting a trial
it's your turn to testify the bailiff
will call you in from the hallway or
waiting room where you've been waiting
the bailiff is a peace officer
and remains in the courtroom during the
trial to ensure
it is a safe place
then you and the court advocate will go
into the courtroom
remember the court advocate assigned to
your case
will be with you the whole time the
court advocates job is to meet with you
before you ever go to court to let you
know what to expect
they are there to answer your questions
provide moral support
and to be with you during your time in
the courtroom
after you enter the court you will be
escorted to the witness stand
where you will take the oath this oath
is your promise that the information you
give as
testimony will be the truth
as you take your seat in the witness
chair you will probably notice someone
nearby
typing into a machine that looks like a
small typewriter
this is the court reporter who makes the
complete record of everything that
happens during a trial
it is important for witnesses testifying
to answer questions loudly
and clearly it is important to give
verbal answers
not shrugs or nods the information taken
down by the court reporter is also
sometimes used
by the jury when they deliberate the
case to refresh themselves about the
facts that were brought out
and who said what next to the witness
chair is the judge's bench
the judge is in charge of the courtroom
the judge runs the trial
and makes certain all the rules are
properly followed
judges also make rulings during the
course of the trial
when either the defense attorney or the
prosecutor
makes any objections to any questions
being asked
in the middle of the courtroom are the
tables for the defense
and the prosecution the defense attorney
sits at the defense table
it is the job of the defense attorney to
make certain the defendant gets a fair
trial the defense attorney attempts to
create
reasonable doubt in the juror's minds in
hopes of getting the defendant a not
guilty verdict and the prosecutor sits
at the other table
it's the prosecutor's job to present the
case for the state
to present the evidence against the
defendant
the prosecutor is also there to help
protect
witnesses like you from being harassed
or badgered
by the defense attorney the judge's job
is to make certain
that only the relevant facts are
presented
and the judge is also there to protect
you when you're on the witness stand
by making rulings on the types of
questioning allowed
the judge can help prevent a witness
from being badgered
by the attorneys most cases are tried
before a jury
they are those people sitting together
on the side in the area
called the jury box the people on the
jury are supposed to be impartial
they don't know the participants from
either side of the case
they listen carefully to all evidence
presented by
all of the witnesses called to testify
when the defense and prosecution both
rest and give their closing statements
then the jury goes into another room to
deliberate and discuss the case
it's their job to weigh all of the
testimony and evidence then they decide
if the evidence presented is enough
to find the defendant guilty their
decision
is the verdict sometimes they find the
defendant guilty
sometimes they give a not guilty verdict
and sometimes if they can't agree on the
verdict they are hung
and it's possible the case will have to
be retried in front of a new jury
in some instances there are people
watching the trial seated behind the
rail in the back of the courtroom
they may be people you know but usually
they're not involved in your case
the judicial process can be scary if
you've never been involved with it
[Music]
you