[Music]
let's look at the size of rain and how
raindrops fall first we'll need the Sun
when the Sun shines on water on the
Earth's surface the heat of the Sun
warms the water turning it into an
invisible gas called water vapour this
process the changing of water into a gas
is called evaporation because gases are
lighter than liquids water vapor rises
up into the sky and the further you move
up and away from the Earth's surface the
code and the temperature gets so in the
sky the water vapor cools and changes
back into tiny water droplets this
change is called condensation and is the
opposite of evaporation clouds are made
up of tiny water droplets so when
condensation occurs in the sky clouds
form and grow let's take a closer look
when water droplets bump into one
another they stick together and grow in
size they continue to grow until they
are too heavy and fall as rain
they even grows they bump into one
another on their journey from the cloud
to the ground and every single raindrop
that reaches the ground is made up of 1
million of the original tiny water
droplets
[Music]
raindrops fall on the ground surface or
the Sun can shine on them and the whole
process happens again this is called the
water cycle and keeps water moving from
the ground to the sky providing the
water needed for plants animals and
people to survive so now you know