[Music]
hey it's pip demerit dragon and mr. pit
bulls and we're finalists from season 10
of America's Got Talent
the great thing about this show is it's
the best of the best from all over the
world so just getting to the competition
that's priced enough at least that's
what I'm telling the dog but he's not
buying it after we left a GT we flew
back to Vegas the next day we got a show
we got our own show v a magic dragon
show at the Flamingo Hotel and Casino
mr. pibbles and I just got the theater
renamed the pit the Mediterranean
theater highly mr. poofles would like to
offer you a complimentary green cleaning
service would you like that it's very
good it's been cleaning as I ring for
years tonight on stage we did a new bit
and that we've been working on for the
past few months getting ready for
Champions now hide it mr. pibbles is
gonna lick all of the food out of your
ring leaving it as gleaming as the day
that you bought it for yourself mr.
pibbles cleaned one of Heidi's rings and
well Heidi seemed happy with the results
on the count of three give them a
squeeze one two three
lovely good sure buddy
the judges will greet it was great to go
in there and hear what they have to say
because mr. pibbles and I we haven't won
America's Got Talent
we were back here as runners-up slash
losers you have been one of the best
ambassadors for the show to give people
trust to come on the show so I owe you a
lot
thank you goodbye thanks guys
hi YouTube click below to subscribe for
more talent