when talking about the Balkans ethnic
hate between group is not an uncommon
topic however there is seldom a group of
people hated more than
[Music]
the
gyps gypsies arguably the gypsies also
known as the Roma have also been an
Inseparable part of Balkan culture and
its history however due to generational
stigma Prejudice and more importantly
lack of research very little is known
about them as a result even though
they've more or less developed parallel
to the other peoples in the region and
played an equally important role in its
history and its development the vast
majority of people have been left
stigmatized and shunned from the
spotlight and labeled as unwanted
nuisances yet if you dig a bit deeper
past the stereotypes of Thieves and
black magic casters you can discover a
fascinating colorful and quite tragic
history of Europe's most hated group
for the longest of times the origin of
the gypsies has been shrouded in mystery
even though they've been very much
present in the Balkans and in Europe
since the 13th century most balanoides
weren't even aware that they were a
separate ethnic group the gypsies as
migration to the continent coincided
with a series of Wars between the selic
Turks and the byzantines as a result the
first Gypsy arrivals were mistaken and
dismissed by the byzantines as just more
Turks as the wars between the Christian
forces of Europe and Muslim forces of
the Turks continued crusading Germans
and a French named the people sarakan or
sarasan meaning heathens as the years
passed by the Europeans eventually
became aware of them being separate from
the Turks so the Greeks named them at
singani which carried a similar meaning
to the one imposed by the Crusaders yet
it roughly translated to don't touch
marking the gypsies as The Untouchables
yet even though the original word at
singani has has lost its meaning a long
time ago today most of the Balkan and
Eastern European languages word for the
gypsies still comes from this word
taking various forms such as sigani
sigani and siga nonetheless after the
Roma became a concert presence
throughout the continent more theories
about their origin sprung up throughout
Medieval Europe many could be found in
particular around the coastal areas of
the Adriatic and had quite darker skin
than the locals I know quite difficult
to believe when the average Greek looks
like this but this is the strong sperm
this the GRE gold okay GRE because of
this a new Theory came up being that
they originated from Egypt the theory
became further popularized as the egyps
themselves were unaware of their origin
either due to being a nomatic people and
lacking a written language they also
started to believe that their actual
Homeland was Egypt and began to refer to
themselves as Egyptians as a result the
term Gypsy meaning Egyptian was born
from this Theory with many other
European countries is adopting a similar
word to their language such as jupi Gano
and Yos so for the next 400 years
practically everyone in Europe including
the gypsies themselves assumed that the
land of denial was their true land of
origin it wasn't up until the
enlightenment when people actually
started to put this Theory to the test
what's even more ironic the study of
gypsy AKA Romani studies came about
because of an accident when in 760 a
Hungarian student in Holland who knew a
couple of words in Gypsy he learned from
his servant back at his estate in J
noticed similarities to the language
being spoken between two Indian exchange
students he told this to his friend and
acquaintance as an interesting anecdote
which start to spread through bars and
cafes until a German journalist took
interest in the story he published it in
an Austrian newspaper in 1776 from which
various linguists across the continent
then became interested and subsequently
started a new field of study just
because of some students's story
practically overnight the myth of Egypt
that was believed for over the past 400
years was dispelled and the first
connection to India was made so uh if
you haven't thanked your Town's local
Hungarian for his contribution to
society Now's the
Time since the late 1700s various origin
theories have come about the Gypsies in
Germany popular theories arose that
because of their Greek name at singani
the gypsies were actually gretan
Heretics that came from the African
provinces of Zana others speculated that
the Bible already gave the answer of
their origin as they were the cursed
descendants of Cain condemned to wander
the Earth for eternity as God has cursed
the soil they plowed so nothing would
grow from it a little less spectacular
than the theory of how Yak created white
people but still it has a similar Vibe
this theory was also believed because
the Roma didn't have a religion of their
own so with Europe being the prime
breeding ground of religious zismo
speculations on the gypsies as origin
came to life one of my personal favorite
Legends comes from the Romanians and
serbs the Romanians stipulated that in
the beginning the Gypsies and Romanians
built two churches the gypsies made
theirs out of stone while the Romanians
made theirs out of ham the gypsies then
persisted and haggled with the Romanians
to trade until the Romanians finally
agreed once getting the ham Church the
Gypsy subsequently at it which forced
them to become Eternal Godless wanders
the serbs version is practically the
same but says that the church was built
out of cheese instead and adds on to the
explanation of their begging being that
they beg from the serbs because they
still owe the money for their Church
however unsurprisingly the true origin
of the Roma is much less schizophrenic
through linguistic and later on genetic
analysis it was found that their first
origin was in Northwestern India in a
region known today as Punjab up until
the 11th century the gypsies were
indistinguishable from many other
peoples that inhabited the different
kingdoms of this region however around
the year 1000 the gavid Empire Rose to
prominence and began to encroach on the
territories of the regional Kingdoms in
Northern India as the gavit seek to
expand the other kingdoms and
principalities within the subcontinent
resisted which sparked hundreds of
bloody battles which resulted in
enormous casualties and rendered the
regions caught in the fighting as a
sesel of violence and destruction many
who were lucky enough to escape death
weren't lucky enough to be taken as
prisoners of War these prisoners were
then tasked to tend to the gavit
warriors on and off the battlefield this
Bloodshed continued for the next couple
of centuries as the gavits and their
successors continue to expanding East
through India with limited success
bringing death and Devastation as they
went eventually many from the region had
enough and decided to Embark West in
search for better lands to settle away
from the cruelty of the gavit Empire
joined by the War prisoners many
embarked on an Epic Journey Through the
Hindu Kush mountains to leave India it
is estimated that the first gypsies took
the route through the SWAT River Valley
or Kagan Valley where they would then
follow the Silk Road which would lead
them through Coran today Afghanistan
usbekistan
Turkmenistan and Iran where they then
continue along the south of the Caspian
Sea through the Caucasus Mountains of
Georgia and Armenia all the way to
trebond Mordor AKA today's turkey
in a relatively short time the gypsies
traversed the celk roow through Persia
with few Clans here and there choosing
to stay in the lands they traversed up
until they arrived in Anatolia by the
time that Rome arrived in the region it
was heavily contested between the
weakening Byzantine Empire and the
expanding Muslim Turks in the late 11th
century many gypsies entered the eastern
most parts of Byzantium where they
acquired a variety of trade jobs in
towns and settlements as they were seen
as out iders they weren't allowed to
ownership over land thus overwhelmingly
flocked to jobs of blacksmiths metal
workers carpenters and entertainers
basically having to resort to the
medieval version of door dashing and
being Glover couriers it is estimated
that the Romani didn't get to Mainland
Europe for another 200 something years
as the first mention of them came in the
late 13th century where several
Egyptians were noted as Tax Collectors
as the Turks pushed westwards the
gypsies increasingly fell under their
Juris section they continued having many
of the same jobs they had in Byzantium
but also started being used within the
military as many gypsies were used as
prisoners of war and even had Warrior
ancestry fighting the gavits the Turks
utilized them in their armies now it's
not known to what extent this was
consensual service and to which it was
slave labor as the gypsies didn't
convert to Islam and there is a lack of
documentation of the earlier
relationship between the Turks and
gypsies however what is known is that a
lot of gypsies entered Europe in the
14th century via military campaigns and
as slave labor employed by the Ottomans
into the Balkans and from there on they
found their way further up the
[Music]
continent by the time constant ople fell
under the Ottomans and byzantium's
existence was only left in our hearts
the gypsies became a widespread presence
in the Balkans the kingdoms
principalities and then subsequently the
provinces of the Ottoman Empire that
resided on the peninsula were mostly
agricultural based societies as a result
not a lot of artisan products were
present throughout the realm however as
the Roma became ever so present in the
region the local nobility and
aristocracy quickly found use of them
because of their craftsmanship skills
Gypsy made items rapidly fill the demand
for these products the goods they could
produce were seen as extremely useful in
trade and commerce and gave an edge to
any Noble who could possess an excess of
them so although they did not own any
land they were taken in as serves by the
local Lords and exploited by being
forced to produce baskets textiles tools
weapons and anything in between because
they were seen as quite valuable the
gypsies would become linked to certain
Estates and property so when an ability
would trade land or give it as a gift to
one another they would also give away
the gypsies on that land as an abbility
would be given land and subsequently the
gypsies on it so would the clergy and
many monasteries as well soon Gypsy
labor became quite coveted and the
demand for the goods they would produce
in the Balkans only Rose as no one could
get enough of it as a result the
legislature regarding servitude and
gypsies became increasingly stricter in
a way to keep them on that land this
rapidly transformed from a subset of
feudalism to straight up slavery as
Lords in possession of gypsies were
given full unrestricted rights and
control over what was to be done with
the life of his gypsies within the
Balkans slavery over gypsies became ever
more enshrined within the ottom
institutions as the Islamic world viiew
at the time dictated that Muslims had
the right to fully treat any conquered
non-muslim subjects as property as you
can imagine the Roma weren't the only
ones affected by this view as were the
serbs Greeks Romanians bulgarians and
any other Christians within the Empire
however they were impacted the most due
to their already low social status in
particular the Romanian predecessors the
principalities of wahi and mavia eagerly
jumped onto this nasty institution lot
sees also known as the inspiration for
Dracula and the highly esteemed shish
kebab maker is also credited for
bringing the Gypsy slaves to Romania in
1445 after several incursions into
ottoman Bulgaria by the wakan Army sees
brought back around 12,000 gypsies with
him to use as slaves Stefan the great
deemed by the pope athlete of Christ
moldova's favorite person to name things
after today and another highly esteemed
ruler in Romanian history was the second
notable Romanian to bring in a large
batch of gypsy slave labor in 1471 after
a battle against the Turks with the wans
mavian forces captured and transported
over 177,000 gypsies back to the
principality lad Dracula was also quite
fun of using them in his army as well
steepish held a belief that the gypsies
were a Fearless class of Warriors who
would give him a fighting Edge against
the Turks their participation in waka's
war the Ottomans was also described in
the first ever epic poem written in
Romanian in early 1800s the Tanada I
know it sounds like something to come
out of Tu Balan for you but it's real
tig's writer Buddha deu tells how the
brave lot sees LED his army of gypsies
into battle against the Turks where the
Gypsy Warriors fought along angels for
the glory of Christendom anyways by the
time all of the Balkans fell under the
Muslims and went into economic and
cultural Decay wahia and mavia were able
to prosper in part this was due to them
never being fully controlled by the
Ottomans but also due to them heavily
relying unslaved labor of the gypsies
who they exploited for their economic
gain the principalities were so
dependent on them economically that they
had to start importing more and more
gypsies to keep up with demand
practically becoming the Confederacy way
before the Confederacy was even a thing
because of this Romania to this day has
the largest number of gypsies in any
country in the world by the 1500s the
institution of gypsy slavery in the
Balkans came to resemble that of African
slavery in America 100 years before the
first black slaves even touched the
continent much like slavery in the new
world slavery in the Balkans was also
divided into different categories some
of the more prominent categories were
house slaves field slaves slaves of the
crown and slaves of the church the ones
with the hardest jobs and worse
treatment were field slaves who were
condemned to work hard labor and forced
to live in mud huts on the outskirts of
the estate Church slaves on the other
hand had more service-based jobs such as
cooks and Coachmen while house slaves
were tested with taking care of the
household the male house slaves would
also majority of the time be castrated
as to not possess a threat to the female
members of the household while female
house slaves were very often used for
sexual entertainment of the guests and
hosts children born out of this
entertainment were then also condemned
to the fate of slavery and put into
bondage within the estate or sold off in
16th century wahia the exchange rates
for Gypsy slaves were as follows one
Gypsy for one Pig a team of gypsies for
a team of oxen or horses a newly wet
couple for a few barrels of wine a gypsy
girl for a pair of copper pots and a
gypsy with a disability was worth a jar
of honey it was also possible to
purchase half a gypsy which entitled a
pregnant woman and a child she would
bear if a gypsy was stopped by a
government official they had to State
the name of their Master if they
couldn't they would be considered
automatically as property of the crown
thus gypsies in passing who wandered
from region to region would often get
rounded up and taken into bondage which
is why many tended to avoid highly
populated areas and stick to the
outskirts of society as a result not all
gypsies became slaves and many managed
to remain free by doing this as you can
imagine the life of an enslaved Gypsy
was not easy to make it even harder
their overseers known as vavs would more
often than not be extremely cruel and
torture was prevalent although ottoman
law stipulated that killing your slave
was forbidden many did not follow this
and rarely if ever faced punishment for
breaking it as a result many gypsies
fled and went into hiding into the
carpatian mountains where they formed
hidden settlements along other skps by
the early 1800s the Ottomans tried to
regulate the institution of slavery more
by enshrining stricter laws regarding
ownership and treatment of gypsy slaves
however in 1826 the Ottomans were
defeated by the Russians in one of their
many wars and the two remaining
principalities fell outside of Turkish
influence soon after a sta anti-slavery
government Paul Kel was appointed as
governor in the region who aimed to
abolish the practice however due to the
institution being extremely popular with
the Romanian nobility kisela was only
able to pass stricter laws regarding the
regulation of the trade and treatment of
gypsies but was never able to outright
ban the practice now despite the Balkans
being the epicenter of gypsy bondage
this barbaric oppression of the Roma
wasn't only present there nor just in
the ottoman realm as the gypsies made
their way into the Balkans thousands
continued north and west deeper into
Europe soon much of the same laws came
about in Western European countries as
well and gypsies were automatically
assumed of as property and England
captured gypsies were to be branded with
the letter V and be put into slavery for
2 years if they escaped and were then
recaptured they were to be rebranded
with a letter S and made slaves for the
rest of their lives in Iberia both the
Spanish and Portuguese Enslaved the
gypsies as well and exported them to
their colonies in the new world where
they would be used as slave labor on
cash crop plantations in a dark ironic
twist the Portuguese even exported them
back to their colonies in India where
they had left as free men but returned
as individuals in bondage while in
colder and rougher climate regions such
as in Scotland and Russia they were
subject to work in the mines there was
practically no place on the continent
where the gypsies could wander risk-free
and their mere presence in any City
would entail enslavement for the rest of
their
lives by the mid 19th century the
Industrial Revolution was starting to
take good hold of Europe and with it it
brought numerous new machines and
inventions such as the spinning mule and
cotton genin that made the use of large
number of labors obsolete thus
throughout Western Europe slavery
overall start to be abolished and within
the remaining principalities who wish to
prove their europeanness and establish
stronger ties with France their long
lost Brothers the practice of holding
dripsy slaves start to be seen as
barbaric backwards and most importantly
inhumane in 1837 Alexandro gika the then
governor of the territories passed a law
to free a couple of thousand slaves in
his governorship although it was a small
step it set the ball rolling mavia in
1842 abolished slavery and 5 years later
the wakan church criminalized the
practice as well in 1848 as the
hungarians were fighting the revolution
against the hapsburgs students in
Bucharest protested the practice and
tore down statues in the capital
relating to the institution and voted
for its abolition in the same year this
newly found freedom of the gypsies were
shortlived however as the two
principalities were pushed back into
direct foreign influence by the Russian
Turkish convention which also brought
back old laws including that of slavery
it wasn't until 1855 when more political
events came to fruition and mavia
unanimously passed a bill Banning the
practice and wahia doing the same one
year later in 1856 slavery wasn't fully
stamped out until the first Romanian
unification of 1864 when Prince Yan
kuuza restored the gypsies to their
former Estates and proclaimed them as
free people under them although AB ition
had set the gypsies finally free after
over four centuries of bondage no
programs nor institutions were set in
place to help the newly freak population
acclimate into society the gypsies were
still greatly discriminated against and
had no ways of securing any sort of land
which push them to the fringes of
society many as a result returned back
to the nomatic way of life traversing
the continent from country to Country
working as entertainers musicians
fortune tellers and
[Music]
Traders
however between the late 19th century
and the mid 20th century race realism
became an Ever more popular pseudo
science that over the years took a
greater and Tighter grip over Europe and
the world as a whole in particular in
the late 1800s Germany became a major
hub for these ideas many German authors
and experts in a topic referred to both
the Jews and gypsies as excrement of
human ity even highly esteemed English
scientists Charles Darwin responsible
for introducing and popularizing the
theory of evolution and being the bane
of existence for American Evangelical
parents in school described the Gypsies
in his writing as not being culturally
Advanced like territorially settled
peoples as a result a series of
anti-gypsy laws were being passed that
continually worsen the lives of the Roma
all over Europe and drove them to even
further fringes of society htic laws
within Germany he criminalized many
gypsies due to prohibiting the lack of
having a permanent home or job and not
being on the taxpayer register in the
1880s German Chancellor F bismar
reinforced and introduced stricter
discriminatory laws against the Romas
stating that the gypsies are to be dealt
with especially severely if apprehended
10 years later in 1890 the ziga gishmas
AKA Gypsy scum Conference was held in
swabia where the nation's military was
given explicit authorization to keep the
gypsies on the move at the turn of the
century in 1899 the Gypsy information
agency was set up in Munich which
cataloged data on all gypsies registered
in Germany 6 years later in 1905 this
data was published in a ziga B the Gypsy
book which in 350 Pages described the
gypsies as a plague the German people
must defend themselves against via the
use of Ruthless punishments and which
condemned race mixing and the dilution
of the country's Jee pool alongside this
the book also contained a registry of
every single Gypsy known in Germany
their genealogical details criminal
records and photographs in 1920 the
legal oppression of gypsies became worse
as they became forbidden to enter public
spaces such as parks and public baths in
1925 a series of laws were passed that
required all unemployed gypsies to be
sent to work camps for six security
reasons 2 years later all romanis had to
be registered with the police and every
Gypsy individual children included had
to carry an ID card with their photo and
fingerprints in the same year the
central office for the fight against the
Gypsies in Germany was established and
in 1933 before the Nazis even held power
in Austria the country called for the
withdrawal of all civil rights from the
romanis in the same decade more laws
were passed where marriage between
Gypsies and non- gypsies was strictly
prohibited and for sterilization of
Romani women was introduced as well by
1938 the final solution for the gypsies
was first mentioned by the Nazis and
soon became quite popular and plans
started to be prepared by the time World
War II officially started several
massacres and pograms of gypsies took
place all throughout Germany and German
occupied territory and then in 1942 it
was ordered for all romanis to be
deported to aitz binau where they would
be exterminated much like the Jews and
many others who were barbarically put
into these camps the gypsies too
suffered tremendous torturous conditions
and torture by the Nazis they were also
Prime targets of medical experiments
with ysf mangala a dreaded Nazi
scientist taking a special interest in
brutally experimenting on them because
of YouTube's policies I won't go further
into detail on what went on in this Camp
however I implore you to do your reading
on this chapter of history as it is
quite often forgotten the treatment of
the Gypsies in the Holocaust was
disregarded so much so that even the
Nazis did not track the exact numbers of
the Roma they murdered often riding
their casualties as Jews or Russians as
a result it is estimated that between
500,000 and 1 and a half million gypsies
were brutally murdered in a variety of
ways during this gruesome part of
History so unfortunately we will never
know the exact number of their
[Music]
victims
after Germany was defeated the
imprisoned gypsies were once again free
even though they went to hell and back
neither support nor help was given to
the victims after they were freed by the
allies during the nurg trials the
gypsies didn't even receive a delegation
in the prosecution of the perpetrators
nevertheless they were at least free to
go back to their homes or so they
thought as one nasty ideology was slain
another popped its ugly head communism
even though the Communists aimed to free
the average labor from his chains they
did the exact opposite to the gypsies
one of the first laws they passed
throughout the Socialist world was that
of prohibiting wandering as a way to
Outlaw gypsies from being Nomads like
they were many were forcibly assigned to
Industrial towns and cities where they
were forced to go back to work at
factories or Farms as a way of
assimilating their population into the
workforce and nation in Bulgaria for
example the Gypsy identity was banned
outright declaring yourself as EG Gypsy
and the national census was not allowed
and the Roma were forced to declare
themselves as either Bulgarian or
Turkish and subsequently even forced to
adopt Bulgarian or Turkish names however
not all was bad because of these
authoritarian governments and the severe
penalties for breaking the laws they
enacted hate crimes and ethnic targeting
of gypsies was almost non-existent many
were given State man ated apartments and
homes for the first time ever but to be
fair in many cases these homes were
known to be subpar and although they had
to live in different bonds they weren't
targeted for their ethnicity which
allowed them to live semi-normal lives
as a result in Romania the only group of
people that ever had anything positive
to say about the cha chesus Romania's
communist dictatorial power couple are
the Roma nevertheless with the fall of
Communism so fa the protection many
gypsies enjoyed by the state in the
early '90s a series of programs against
the gypsies took place throughout
Transylvania in Romania as both the
hungarians and Romanians living there
collaborated together on kicking out the
gypsies from their villages usually one
person from the Gypsy Community would
commit a terrible crime which then
prompted all of the other villagers to
band together and burn down the houses
of the other Gypsies and expel all of
them from their Village as a way of
collective punishment more often than
not the police would be in on it or just
simply not care at the Injustice taking
place a lot of the time the Crim someone
from the Roma committee would commit
would be fictional even as the gypsies
always had to adapt to survive when
capitalism started to be embraced many
quickly jumped on board and open up
their own businesses such as cafes and
restaurants many Gypsy families
especially in rural Villages quickly
became sort of Rich from such Endeavors
which then prompted their neighbors to
assume that they got rich via theft from
the community thus sometimes it only
took one person to accuse them of a
crime an entire Village would then jump
on the w hunt and deal out vigilante
justice these incidents also happen in
other parts of Eastern Europe which
prompted many romanis to abanded their
countries and migrate West into Germany
and other Western European States
throughout the '90s tens of thousands of
gypsies from all over the Eastern block
flocked to Western Poland where they
attempted to cross into Germany and seek
Refuge many would get rid of their
papers along the way to make their case
for Asylum more likely to pass however
this rarely ever worked the majority of
gypsies fleeing into Germany would be
allowed to stay only 2 years in a
refugee camp while their application was
being processed during their stay they'd
find some sort of low paying work either
in the camp itself or the towns nearby
and afterwards they would be kicked back
home while also having their finances
taken from them due to them being
obtained via illegal work in the country
often enough the savings these gypsies
brought would also be taken under that
pretense and basically leave them with
no money whatsoever upon being deported
back to their countries of origin in
many cases the countries would refuse to
take them back as they didn't have any
papers and because the Germans took
their money many were left without a
scent nor passport to their name later
on Germany would PID Romania millions of
marks at the time to take back its
citizens and build housing but as the
government of Romania at the time was
severely corrupt you can imagine how the
story ended today the situation of many
gypsies has improved since the dreaded
'90s but it is still far away from
perfect many programs and NOS have
sprung up to assist Roma communities
throughout Europe however many still
live as outcasts of society and often do
not have adequate infrastructure nor
facilities for a normal life even in one
of Romania's most well-developed cities
CL P an Infamous Gypsy neighborhood
known for its favel like conditions is
allowed to exist virtually ignored by
the government despite the city's
booming it sector however it is also
important to note that many gypsies also
aren't thrilled to jump into cooperating
with a society that has oppressed them
for centuries and only recently led up
on their brutal treatment while
systematic issues exist when it comes to
the treatment of the Roma communities in
Eastern Europe so do trust issues
amongst the Romani who sometimes
willfully refuse attempts of
normalization efforts but hopefully both
will change as more progress takes place
and brighter chapters become written in
the history of the gypsies thank you for
watching this has been quite a brutal
video to research in right as H Gypsy
history is characterized by bondage and
expulsion please let me know what you
think in the comments and if I should do
more of these types of videos in the
future my name is yanos and you've
watched living around a clean Europe hey
hey why are you living in the
USA it is not the place to stay hey hey
I been in my glass if
me don't me that you are gay are G