guys coach Brian Kaki here with my buddy
Chris we're going to turn this park
bench into a little workout
station
n
so take those four exercises which
you're hitting all the muscles of the
body hitting the legs doing some
explosive work and uh getting your
getting your heart rate up a little bit
oh yeah great for calorie burning you
can do that just about anywhere do as
many rounds as you want you can do am
wrap style take 20 minutes do as many
rounds as possible with some water
breaks in between do it for five sets
whatever time yourself with each
exercise there a lot of different ways
to kind of go go at stuff St like that
but fantastic there's no excuses you
don't have equipment you don't have a
gym everybody has a bench somewhere and
they could do those four exercises
thanks so much coach Bryant we'll see
you again soon check the links
below