i've just bought every single
playstation brand new we've got a tv
from the time of each one's release and
even the same game on all of them so
let's find out how much the gaming
experience has evolved over time it
might sound strange now but the original
playstation was actually a massive risk
for sony because put simply sony was a
nobody in 1994 the entire gaming market
was just two companies nintendo who hit
a home run with the creation of mario
and had about 40 market share and sega
who having created sonic their
equivalent to mario had taken the market
by storm to achieve a share of 55
both of these titans were fighting tooth
and nail to try and make their mascot
the greatest 2d platformer of all time
but sony realized something that now is
the perfect time for 3d yeah this is a
real sealed playstation 1 straight from
1994. and inside we've got the video
adapter in case your tv didn't have the
right connectors the ac adapter to plug
into the mains the controller which was
of course wired and the console
hopefully it turns on this is ancient
equipment
that sound that's basically the sound of
a cathode ray gun shooting electrons at
the display panel that's actually why
they're called crt tvs power on the
original playstation
the buttons kind of want to experience
opening the disk drive
it's actually making me kind of sad that
modern technology has no moving parts
listen to this
[Music]
the controller is so light it kind of
feels like it's not even there and also
look at this no analog sticks there's
one thing sony smashed it's buttons this
is so nice now with only two megabytes
of ram a maximum resolution of 480p and
no internal storage the ps1 stats might
sound pitiful by modern standards i
literally had to amazon a 128 kilobyte
storage card for it which is a very
weird thing to do in 2022 but at the
time when it was released at today's
equivalent of 570 this was the most
powerful console money could buy so this
is gran turismo running on the ps1 and
if you compare it to nintendo or sega's
supposed 3d offerings you'll quickly
notice that sony is the only one capable
of rendering real 3d models with real
reflections on the cars it looks insane
in comparison but wait till you see what
the next playstation can do sony also
realized that they couldn't just be more
powerful their brand also had to be
different to nintendo and savers and
their way of doing that was swapping the
controller letters for shapes and it
wasn't because sony loved geometry the
shapes have significance for example the
blue cross and the red circle they
represent yes and no which even now to
this day is still what they're used for
in games sony did also follow up the
original playstation with what's
referred to as the playstation slim but
if i'm being really honest we will be
here forever if we start on the
variations of each console so long story
short this company saw an opportunity
and they absolutely smashed it with the
first playstation they completely wiped
out sega for good and practically pulled
nintendo's pants down coming out of
nowhere with the ps1 becoming the first
console ever to pass 100 million units
sold so how did sony top that
well only by releasing the best-selling
console in the history of consoles
sony's approach to the playstation 2
released in 2000 at about 485 dollars in
today's money so significantly cheaper
than the ps1 can be summed up with one
phrase if it ain't broke don't fix it
the ps2 is evolution not revolution and
the unboxing experience also mirrors
that philosophy you get an upgraded
controller as well as a similar ac cable
and tv adapter to last time oh this
brings back so many memories almost
everything about the ps2 is a direct
no-frills improvement over its
predecessor it comes with about 12 times
the amount of raw processing power
depending on how you measure it 16 times
the amount of ram and no less than 63
times the amount of storage on the
default memory card this had eight
megabytes remember back in the day
consoles didn't used to have these
enormous hard drives inside of them to
be able to install games onto the entire
game would be fit onto the game disc
itself and so the only extra storage you
needed was just a memory card for your
save files which you could then take out
and carry your saves to your friend's
house with so if we turn the ps2 on
ah
this is my childhood so there's an eject
button up here
that sounds amazing you can barely read
the actual text what these things are
that difference is crazy
the difference versus the ps1 is
absolutely night and day the processing
power allows it to render many times the
amount of polygons on screen which
reduces the blocky look of the ps1 error
and the extra ram allows for background
textures to just have way more going on
in them like even the finish line banner
it now blows about in the wind and the
master stroke with the ps2 was how sony
managed to through the design of the
console make it extremely clear that
this was a next-gen bitter kit there's
been a few consoles in the past like
nintendo's wii u that looks so similar
to their last gen counterparts that
people thought that they were just
add-ons
not here the ps2's design is far more
bulky and angular with this grill that
was really meant to evoke the feeling of
an engine something capable of real
power that combined with some of the
best games of the generation led the
playstation 2 to break every record ever
set selling 158 million units you had
nintendo's gamecube and microsoft's
original xbox also around at this time
but they didn't even sell a fifth as
much as the ps2 did and to keep up with
the increasing complexity of the games
sony also upgraded the controller with
something they called dualshock which is
a combination of dual analog sticks and
built-in rumble technology so you can
really feel the the texture of the grass
and if you're not a good driver like me
the texture of the wall sony wasn't
kidding with the word rumble the ps2 was
also technically the first time you
could play your games online but you had
to rely on the individual game
developers to create their own servers
as sony didn't develop their own
infrastructure for online connectivity
until
the playstation 3 arguably the first
sony console to properly herald in the
digital age this time around internet
was a focus hence the included ethernet
cable as well as the tv output cables
and a usb mini cable to charge the
further upgraded now wireless controller
i probably don't need to tell you but
the ps3 was also the boldest console
sony i've ever made look at this
beefcake plus do you recognize that text
yeah that's the spiderman font because
sony owns the spiderman ip and they
thought it would help them to sell more
consoles
it did not the good news is that the ps3
took some notes from the ps2 in the ramp
everything up department the bad news is
that this time that also included the
price to try and make the ps3 feel like
a completely new era in gaming sony had
a special custom cell processor designed
just for it but this was really
expensive pushing the launch price of
this console all the way up to
869 dollars in today's money supremely
pricey especially given the console's
creepy plastic exterior but oh boy was
this thing powerful as a matter of fact
as an overall system it was about 35
times more powerful than the ps2 making
it
384 times more powerful than the ps1
these are ridiculous numbers in fact the
ps3 was so advanced that it was actually
used to build supercomputers including a
truly genius move by stanford university
researchers who developed an app called
folding at home which allowed ps3 users
to dedicate a portion of their super
computing power to aid with complex
protein folding calculations used to
learn more about how to prevent diseases
like alzheimer's he was also pretty good
at games
so i never actually owned a ps3 at
launch but i remember how i felt when my
friend got one for the first time it
really felt like a machine from the
future like i remember being just giddy
with excitement that something of this
power actually existed you also notice
they've actually started putting
attention into how the disks look at
this point and the disk loading
mechanism that's all inside the console
now there's no tray that comes in and
out this console is not quiet or cool
for that matter like an oven back here
and it's only on the home screen you can
kind of see that this is the point where
the console became much more than just a
place to play video games it's the first
time there's a proper home screen that
you would actually want to spend time in
this literally used to be one of the
coolest things in the world to me the
fact that you could change your home
screen color oh yeah the friends tab
i spent a lot of time there you think at
that point that you can't make the same
generational leap again
but this is it and also you can actually
feel the mechanics of the game becoming
more sophisticated as well there's more
physics involved one problem that ps3
owners did used to have though was that
because the on off button was capacitive
their pets would often turn their
consoles off don't get any ideas
so now we have the ps3 gran turismo next
to the ps2 next to the ps1 i can't wait
to complete this line but already the
leap is phenomenal the first key
difference being resolution while the
ps1 is outputting the game at 512 by 240
the ps2 is pushing over three times more
pixels by 852 by 480 and the ps3 was
running at two times that at 1280x720
or in other words for the very first
time true high definition gaming this is
basically the difference between you
going into the settings on this video
and swapping between 240p 480p and 720p
massive but it's not just more pixels
it's also much more complex game effects
one of the most impressive things about
the playstation 3 was its ability to
also handle almost lifelike lighting
shadows and reflections not to mention
vast sprawling backgrounds something
else i'm noticing is is how much nicer
the controller is it's wireless it's
weightier because it's now got an
inbuilt battery and also has motion
sensors built into it and also compared
to the ps2's controller the triggers
just have much more travel they call
this the six axis controller because as
well as all the buttons it could also
pick up how you moved the controller
itself and translate that into the game
even though it was the home to god tier
games like grand theft auto 5 and the
last of us even though is where sony
launched their free online playstation
network service even though it also
doubled as a media machine with full
blu-ray disc compatibility sony really
screwed up that pricing it ended up
selling 84 million units barely half of
the ps2 and was slightly outsold by
microsoft's xbox 360. sony was on the
back foot again they needed to do
something special
thankfully
microsoft did their job for them when
the playstation 4 launched up against
the xbox one in 2013 microsoft screwed
up their marketing so badly that sony
could have re-released the playstation 3
and probably still won the fact that
microsoft forced users to also buy the
kinect camera with the console forced
users to be always online and focused
almost completely on how the next-gen
xbox would work as a tv box rather than
a games console it made it almost too
easy for team blue sony even took to the
stage to rip apart the xbox one's
deliberate inability to play borrowed
games this is how you share your games
on ps4
thanks
and it was pretty much game over at that
point now when you add to this that the
ps4 was also insanely well designed it
starts to make sense why it completely
popped off like check out the new dual
shock 4 controller it incorporates the
dual shock tech from the ps2 controller
and the six axis motion sensing from the
ps3 controller and it makes both aspects
much more refined the analog sticks are
now also further apart and they're
concave for better grip there's a new
share button which reflects the shift to
social gaming plus we've also got an rgb
led light on the front as an identifier
for which player you are a speaker in
the controller itself for a directional
sound experience and even a two inch
touchpad in the middle for menu
navigation i remember the moment that i
got to hold one of these for the first
time and i was just sat there like an
idiot like turning it over and over in
my hands for 10 minutes straight
thinking holy cow this is real the ps4
is about 10 times more powerful than the
ps3 making it the numbers are getting
kind of out of hand at this point about
3 800 times as powerful as the ps1 it
had eight gigabytes of ram which is 32
times the ps3 and 4096 times the
original playstation and not to mention
that because the ps4 is based off a less
custom more standard pc-like
architecture it was way easier for
developers to work with it and fully
extract that power
you know this kind of reminds me of the
really really early days of this channel
i remember when the ps4 launched we had
about 10 000 subscribers i know that
because we used to cover tons of gaming
content at the time but i would stick to
handhelds because i would never dream of
spending this much on one console i know
this section is all about the ps4 but
all i can hear is this ps3 this is
actually quite exciting this is the
first time you can turn the console on
with the controller so this is very much
a refined version of the ps3's home
screen much more blocky in style oh my
god listen to it
it's louder than the ps3
there was me thinking this is going to
be a nice sleek quiet machine i only
half blame sony this room that we're in
is basically a sauna right now boots up
the game you can also tell the text is
way sharper and more readable now you
can actually now pick the exact time of
day of your race and it will affect the
weather conditions accordingly you can
feel such a visceral difference the
density of the crowd the the light
coming right from the sun right so i've
actually filled up a bag with ice just
to cool it down because this is getting
ridiculous i'm gonna lay it on top of
the ice pack in my mind this is what a
modern racing game looks like the game
almost has like an atmosphere that the
other ones lack excuse my driving i can
actually also notice a bit of realistic
damage on my car so upgraded physics too
what do you do with this much power then
well i mean just for starters a further
doubling of the resolution to now 1080p
or full hd the ps4 could happily fill a
40 inch tv and not look like it was
being stretched and it also just gave
developers the headroom to be creative
to build not just detailed backgrounds
but fully open worlds to execute their
visions in their entirety plus they
could now add pretty much any visual
effect they could think of dirt
particles motion blur realistic fog and
it's in these details where you really
feel the difference versus the ps3 so
when you combine all of this with the
fact that the playstation 4 also
launched at a much friendlier 500 in
today's money it's not surprising that
it went on to sell 120 million units
more than doubling microsoft's competing
xbox one it's kind of hard to imagine
how this masterpiece can actually now be
seen as a relic of the past but the ps5
firmly pushes it aside cementing itself
as the wildest most futuristic
playstation to ever exist and sony has
really run with this idea of futurism
everything from the controller to the
console to the headset they launch
alongside it it all shares this two-tone
ultra minimalistic space-age design
philosophy and i freaking love it the
moment i saw the ps5 get announced i
shrieked like what gamer doesn't want a
console that looks like a literal alien
starship and i mean it makes the xbox
series x that it's competing against
look like a prude by comparison there is
also this strangely shaped stand which
actually very cleverly can support the
console either horizontally or
vertically but do the internals keep up
absolutely the playstation 5 dunks on
its predecessor it has two times the ram
at 16 gigabytes and it's called graphics
processing unit is about eight times
more powerful and that's not even
factoring in it's solid state storage
that's at least 50 times faster than the
playstation 4's hard drive and this is
the fun part about compounding multiples
when compared to the original ps1 the
ps5 is approximately 30 000 times more
powerful you could make a bridge of
playstation ones spanning an entire city
and it still wouldn't be able to
outperform a single ps5 let's see how
the ps5 compares i love these leds on
the inside such a classy touch this is
such a fun video as well hey if you want
to see me make a comparison of every
nintendo console ever and the sub to the
channel would be historic
oh my god i'm blinded adjust hdr oh that
is actually one of the new features here
just like insane levels of contrast i
know we're only on the homepage right
now but this screen the one thing you
really notice about the ps5 ui is
everything is very visual and full
screen wow the amount of
buildings you can see you can see
individual settlements over here in the
background okay just look at the
difference in color between this screen
and this screen a lot of that is just
the new high dynamic range i can hear
applause coming through the speaker in
the controller you can even see the
clouds in the sky reflected on the body
of my car and moving in real time oh my
god it's so rumbly okay this is a huge
upgrade even from the ps4 not only is
the resolution now full 4k four times
higher than 1080p the ps5 is also
capable of real-time ray tracing meaning
that instead of pre-baking the light
reflections into a scene like most video
games have done till now this console
can simulate the real physical behavior
of light in real time and how it affects
every single pixel on screen and i can
also feel not just the general rumble
for my engine thanks to dual shock but
also the physical sensation of putting
pressure on the pedal thanks to the new
adaptive triggers in this controller
that can adjust their tension on the fly
every playstation console together in
one frame what a sight imagine what the
ps6 is gonna look like
now as slick as the ps5 does look there
is one way to make it even slicker
these are dark plates and not only do
they make your console matte black but
they add vents to allow more air to pass
through they reduce the temperature on
the inside of the console and they also
trim the corners to make it more compact
much needed with the size of this thing
but it's not just a customization for
the sides of the console you can also
pick up a middle skin to cover up those
unavoidable scuffs on the glossy piano
black plastic i've gone for matte black
all the way around but you can also get
retro grey which is color matched to the
original playstation 1 or just classic
white and if that's still not enough
customization dark plates have one more
trick light scripts these are basically
light filters that you put on top of the
existing lights that your ps5 has to
change the color of them to whatever you
want it to be link below to check out
dark plates to see me buy the weirdest
tech on the entire internet click here
i'll catch you there