[Music]
come on come on come on go wake the
whole cat so this sky is awake so I'm
awake so we have to play middle of the
night I know that but do you want to
build a
snowman oh on I no one's around to the
magic do the
[Music]
magic this is
amazing watch
this hi I'm Olaf and I like warm hug I
love you
[Music]
ol an ice
freak be careful Anna don't
down Anna
mama papa come quick wake
[Music]
up Elsa what have you done this is
getting out of hand
Anna she's I cold it was an accident I'm
sorry
Anna I know what we have to
[Music]
do
[Applause]
help please it's my
[Music]
[Applause]
daughter born with the powers are cursed
born and they're getting stronger you
are lucky it wasn't her heart the heart
is not so easily changed but the head
can be persuaded do what you must I
recommend we remove all magic even
memories of magic to be safe but don't
worry I'll leave the
[Music]
fun but she won't remember that I have
powers it's for the best your power will
only
grow there is Beauty in your magic but
also great Danger
you must learn to control it fear will
be your enemy we will protect her she
can learn to control
[Music]
it but until
then we'll lock the gates we'll reduce
the staff we will limit her contct with
people and keep her powers hidden from
everyone including armor
[Music]
that's
[Applause]
[Music]
get
excuse me oh pardon me what's the rush
it's the first sow of the
Season well be
[Music]
careful Do you want to build a
snowman come on let's go and
play I never see you anymore come out
the door it's like you gone
away us to be B SP and now we not I wish
you would tell me
why do you want to build a
snowman he doesn't help me a
snowman away
Anna
okay
[Music]
bye these gloves will help see you're
good now conceal it don't feel it don't
let it
[Music]
show Do You Want to Build a
Snowman or rider bikes around the
halls I think some company is overdue I
started talking to pictures on the walls
hanging their
jum it gets a little lonely all these
empty rooms just watching the
[Music]
hours I'm scared my Powers just keep
getting stronger Elsa please getting
upset will only make it worse you have
to leave it's a short trip your father
and I will only be gone for a few weeks
be strong Elsa No don't touch me I don't
want to hurt you
[Music]
[Laughter]
let
our deepest sympath these
princess your parents will be greatly
[Music]
missed
Elsa
please I know you're in
there people are asking where youve
been they say have courage and I'm
trying to I'm right out here for you
just let me
we only have each other it's just you
and me what are we going to
[Applause]
do do you want to the
[Music]
[Applause]
Snowman
one the most officious occasion of the
Queen's coronation we welcome visitors
one and all to the kingdom of
Arendelle ah arendel our most mysterious
TR partner open those Gates so I may
unlock your secrets and exploit your
riches did I just say that out loud
oopsie I can't believe they're finally
opening up the gates and for a whole
[Music]
day
hey what is all the hubub your sister 's
coronation man my sister's
coronation coronation
day it's coronation day oh the window is
open so that door I didn't know think to
that anymore we Sal
ples for years I've Ro these empty Halls
why have a ballroom with no balls
finally they're opening up the gates
they'll be actual real life people it'll
be totally strange but wow am I so ready
for this
change for the first time in
forever without music there'll be
light for the first time in
forever I'll be danceing through the
night don't know if I'm a lady or gas
but I'm somewhere in that Z cuz for the
first time in
forever I won't be alone I can't wait to
meet
everyone what if I meet no
one tonight imag me down and all
touchingly dve against the wall the
picture most s fisticated
Grace W I suddenly see who standing
there a beautiful stranger tall and fair
I want to stuff some chocolate in my
face but then we laugh and talk all
evening we just t
a nothing like for life I so
far for the first time in
forever they'll be magic they'll be
f for the first time in
forever could be noticed by
someone and I know it is totally crazy
to dream my
f For The First Time in
Forever at least I've got a
[Applause]
chance oh no no no no no no no no
no doing
anything
w
wow
[Music]
let them
see be the good girl you always have to
be
conceal don't feel put on a
show make one wrong move and everyone
will
know it's only for today it's only for
today
I to wait tell the to open up the
G for the first
time true
love tomorrow so it has to be
today cuz for the first time in
forever for the first time in
forever nothing's in my
[Applause]
way
so that
happened I am so sorry are you
hurt oh um okay I'm F I just wasn't
watching where I was
going um this is awkward oh not because
you're awkward just because I'm awkward
you're gorgeous wait what Prince Hans of
the Southern aisle uh Princess Anna of
arendel Princess my lady oh no no that
princess I mean if you hit my sister
also that would have been
yes like you just me just you oh we
should
probably I mean I should sort of got a
thing good
[Music]
talk
worthy queen of
great the heart
of we Crown you
with
[Music]
your majesty the
gloves Simon held
in
actor from fur ear Boer Queen Elsa of
arendel Queen
Elsa this way my
lady I
[Music]
didn't
here are you
sure
Hi H hi me oh hi you look beautiful
thank you you look beautifuler not
Fuller you don't look thank you your
majesty the Duke of weaseltown whistl
the Duke of
whistl your
majesty as your closest partner in trade
might I have the pleasure of the first
day
[Music]
dance and I is a peacock I'm sorry but I
don't dance well then it makes might I
say how wonderful it is to have the
gates open again why were they close I
have you feel like
sharing this way
Duke an honor to meet you
[Music]
both
so this is what a party looks like it's
warmer than I thought and what is that
wonderful
smell
[Music]
chocolate this is so nice I wish I could
feel like this all the
time me too I really do are but it can't
why not just
can't
[Music]
excuse me for a
minute whoa glad I caught
you are you
okay shall
[Music]
we we often have the whole pilot to
myself just alive oh
sorry I got
[Music]
you your physique helps I'm
sure hey what's this oh I was born with
it although I dreamt I was kissed by a
troll
I like
[Music]
it oh I'm
sorry should we be getting back
we've been talking for almost 3 hours
now we have not it's true just like
that's saying you know time flies when
you're well you
know I can't wait to tell my brothers
about you they'll be so jealous how many
brothers do you have 12 yeah count them
all older three of them pretended I was
invisible literally for 2
years yeah but that's what brothers do
and
sisters Elsa and I were really close
when we were little
and and then one day she just shut me
out and I never knew why I would never
shut you
out okay can I just say something crazy
I love crazy all my life has been a
series of doors in my face then suddenly
I talk into you I was thinking the same
thing is like I've been searching my
whole life to find my own place and
maybe it's the party talking or the
chocolate fond but with you but with you
I and
it's before is an Open
Door Love is an Open
Door is an open door with you with you
with you
[Music]
window I mean it's crazy we finish each
other sandwiches that's what I was going
to say never met some so
like have but one
explanation you and were meant to be say
goodbye say goodbye to the pain of the
past we don't have to feel it
anymore Love is an Open
Door is an Open
Door might so much with you with you
with you with you
[Applause]
open
[Music]
back
the come
[Music]
on say goodbye say goodbye to the pain
of the past we don't have to feel it
anymore
Lo an Open
Door an open
door so much more with you with you you
with you an Open
Door okay can I say something crazy will
you marry me can I say something even
crazier
yes
we my
sister sorry so sorry EXC SC thank
you oh this one
oh EXC me there she is
Elsa me Queen me again uh may I
introduce Prince Hans of the Southern
ises Your Majesty we would like your
blessing of our marit
marriage I'm sorry I'm confused oh oh
well we haven't worked out all the
details ourselves we need a few days to
play the ceremony of course we have fro
and ice cream oh wait would we live here
here absolutely we invite all 12 of your
brothers to stay with us wait wait slow
down no one's brothers are staying here
no one is getting married wait what you
can't marry a man you just met you can
if it's true love Anna what do you know
about true
love more than you all you know how to
do is shut people
out I'm sorry Anna you asked for my
Lessing but my answer is no the party is
over close the gates give me my cloth
please please you have doing what's best
for both of us I can't live like this
anymore then
leave why would you what did I ever do
here enough no why why you shut me out
why do you shut the world out what are
you so afraid of I said
enough sorcery are you there something
do weird going on here
monster she not
monst he's s he's swing in the middle of
July the
que he's a monster I tell you please
just stay away for me all of you just
stay away wait you can't go after her
this is all my fault I pushed her so I'm
the one that needs to go after her I
leave Prince Hans in charge are you sure
you can trust her I don't want you
getting hurt she's my sister she would
never hurt
[Music]
me
[Applause]
[Music]
snow glows white mountain
to to be
SE A kingdom of
isolation looks like I'm the
Queen the wind is howling like this
swirling
storming couldn't keep it in heav knows
I don't let them don't let them see be
the good girl You' always had to be
concealed don't feel don't let them
know
now
they let it go let it go can't hold it
back
anymore let it go let it go turn
away the
door I don't care what they're going to
say let the stor
r never bother me
[Music]
anyway it's funny how distance makes
everything seem small and the once
control can't get to me at
all it's time to see what I can do to
test the limit and break through no
right no wrong no rules for
me find
free Let it go Let it go I am one with
the wind and sky let it go let it go
you'll never see me
cry here I
said that here I'll
stay let the stor r
my power flurries through the
air
around my soul sping in
Frozen all around around and one the
cryst is like an icy
BL never go back the past is in
the let it go let go
and let it go let it go that perfect
girl is
done here I stand in
the
day
let
the the cold never bothered me
anyway oh
[Music]
what the
this is what you get for calling me a
[Music]
crook a big summer BL
byebye sorry Spen no carrots but
Kristoff you promised let me make it up
to you how's about a
lullabie but I can't eat a
lullabie
[Music]
Reindeers Are Better Than People Spen
don't you think that's true yeah people
will beat you and curse you and cheat
you every one of them's bad except you
thanks
buddy
gross but people smell better than
reindeers Sven don't you think I'm
right that's once again true for all
except you oh you got me let's call it a
night good
night don't let the frost
bite
[Music]
by excuse me huh that's another young
woman I don't know the queen perhaps
pass for these parts
pleas hello now I can use a little help
right about now you could use a little
help I sell ice for a
living oh that is a rough business to be
in right now D unfortunate tell me about
it hey maybe we can help each other I
need you to take me up the North
Mountain I don't take people
places let me rephrase that I and
Princess Anna of Arendelle and I want
you to take me up the North Mountain
please
fine get
in Kristoff
Spen so what exactly are we looking
for uh my sister she started this whole
winter in the middle of summer thing
people are calling her a monster but it
was all my fault
see I got engaged then she freaked out
because I don't believe just met him you
know that day and she said she wouldn't
bless the marriage wait you got engaged
to someone you just met that day yep so
anyway I got mad and then she got mad
and she tried to walk away and I tried
to grab a hang on you mean to tell me
you got engaged to someone you just met
that day yeah yeah can we folus here so
the thing was she wore the gloves all
the time so I thought maybe she have
something thing about her didn't your
parents ever warn you about
strangers yes they did but Hans is not a
stranger this is true love it doesn't
sound like true love to me are you some
sort of love expert no but I have
friends who are oh your friends are love
experts I'm not buying stop talking no
really I'd love to
meet
why what do we do let me handle it help
no why not because I don't your judgment
excuse me who marries a man she just met
I told
you w nice
shot
out
no there's a h t over ahead that's how
we lose them are you ready for this I
was boring ready don't
[Music]
s
fall
[Music]
ow are you okay I'm okay
thanks how's your head oh that's fine I
mean I'm good um I've got a thick skull
so I don't have a
skull
or where did you come from hi I'm Olaf
and I like warm hugs Olaf that's right
Olaf did Elsa build you yeah why do you
know where she is yeah why do you think
you can show us the way
yeah I'll tell you why we need Elsa to
bring back summer
summer oh I don't know why but I've
always loved the idea of Summer and sun
and all things hot really I'm guessing
you don't have much experience
with heat nope but sometimes I like to
close my eyes and imagine what it'll be
like when summer does
come beel Bus kids will blow dandon fuds
and I'll be doing whatever up is in
summer
hi a drink in my hand my snow up against
the burning sand probably getting
gorgeously T in summer
I'll finally see a summer freeze blow
away a winter storm and find out what
happens to solid water when it gets
war and I can't wait to see well my bud
all think of me just imagine how much
cooler I'll be in
[Music]
summer
oh a
pic the hot and the cold both so intense
put them together and just makes
sense Winter's a good time to stay in
and cuddle but put me in summer in
AIA happy
sowman when life to hold on dream
relaxing in the sunmer sun just let
not oh the sky will
beue and you guys will be there
too when I finally do but Frozen things
do in
summer I'm going to tell him I tell you
dare
[Applause]
it's CL does anyone need a cloak and the
castle is open there is soup and hot vog
in the Great Hall prin H are we just
expected to sit here and freeze while
you give away all the barend Del's
tradable Goods Princess Anna left me in
in
[Music]
charge and I'll do whatever I can to
help the citizens of Arendelle the
weather's get be W by the minute and
there's been no sign of Princess Anor in
some time the people are
worried perhaps you're right I will go
and find her at
once me my Lord I follow to two men to
accompany
you
be prepared for anything and should you
encounter the queen you are to put an
end to this winter you
[Music]
understand Elsa it's me Anna
Anna you look so different I feel
different it's a good
difference and this place is amazing
thank you I never knew what I was
capable of I'm so sorry about what
happened cuz if I oh no it's okay you
don't need to apologize it's so
wonderful to see you but you should
probably go please I just got here you
belong in arand
Elsa we were so close we can be like
that again no we can't Elsa please I'm
just trying to protect you you don't
have to protect me I'm Not
Afraid please don't shut me out again
please don't slam the door you don't
have to keep your distance
anymore cuz for the first time in
forever I finally understand For The
First Time in Forever we can fix this
hand in hand we can head down this
mountain together we have to live in
fear for the first time in
forever I will be right here onor please
back
home your life
Waits go enjoy the sun and open out the
again yeah I know mean
well believe me be yes I'm alone but I'm
alone and free just stay away and you'll
be safe from
me actually we're not what do you mean
you're not I get the feeling you don't
know what do I not know Aon tells in
deep deep deep deep
snow what you kind of set off an eternal
winter everywhere everywhere but it's
okay just a three it no I can't I don't
know how can't I no you can't cuz for
the first
time such a fool I can't
be
froming I can't control the
reverse pleas you all make it wor
there's so
much we can't face this thing together
Anna are you okay I'm okay I'm fine who
is he wait it doesn't matter you have to
go no I know that we can figure this out
together how what power do you have to
stop this winter to stop me Anna I think
we should go no I'm not leaving here
without you Elsa yes you are
Anna your hair it's turning white what
it's what it's because she struck you
isn't
it does it look
bad no you hesitated no I didn't Anna
you need help now come with me where are
we going to see my friends the love
expert yes and don't worry they'll be
able to fix this come on Sven come on
Olaf hey i' like to consider myself a
bit of a love
expert chck
buddy right
[Music]
now
hello
[Music]
my
hey um so about my friends they're
actually more like family they took get
SP in me when we were just kids and had
no one they sound wonderful yeah they
sort of are well anyway here everybody
is meet the
family Christ home
[Applause]
girl Bright
House working
no strong tee oh yes yes yes she'll do
nicely for our Crystal oh no no you've
got the wrong idea that's not why I
brought her here what's the issue dear
why are you holding back from such a
is it the clumpy way he walks or the
grumpy way he talks or the peir shake
squ shake weirdness
of and we know Hees well he always of
smell never
ative and
[Music]
sweet few
FL your braind deer with the ree has a
little outside
pictures
enough she's engaged to somebody else
okay so she's a bit of a fixer uper
that's a minor thing engagement is
[Music]
[Applause]
arrangement
[Music]
we are say change you people don't
really
change saying that love is powerful and
strange people make bad
[Applause]
choices everyone
brother the only fixer fix like fix raer
is do you are not to P off to be your
truy
wait what you're cting
[Applause]
[Music]
mared
Anna she's cold as ice let me examine
her Anna your life is in danger there is
ice in your heart put there by your
sister if not removed to solid ice will
you freeze forever I know so remove it
Grand pabby I cannot if it was her head
that would be easy but only an act of
true love can thaw a frozen heart an act
of true love a true love's kiss
perhaps
Anna we have to get you back to Hans
Hans come on Sven Olaf I'm coming let's
go kiss
Hans who is this Hans
than
[Music]
[Applause]
h
here bring her close to the
fire you're so cold what happened Queen
Elsa struck her with her powers thank
you for bringing her back and there's
soup and hot no I don't I didn't just
please make sure she's
safe I thought you said she would never
hurt
you I was
wrong I'll froze my heart and only an
act of true love can save me true love's
kiss
[Applause]
[Music]
kiss if only there was someone out there
who loved
you you
did 13th in line in my own kingdom I
knew I would have to marry into the
throne somewhere Elsa was preferable but
you you were so desperate for love you
were willing to marry me just like that
besides she doomed herself and you ran
after her now she's hidden away in the
palace
dungeon all that's left to do is kill
Elsa and bring back summer you're no
match for Elsa no you're no match for
Elsa I on the other
hand I'm the hero that's going to save
Arendelle from destruction
you won't get away with this
sh I already
have
Anna oh
no what happened to hun what happened to
your
kiss I was wrong about him it wasn't
true love
I don't even know what love
is oh well that's okay I
do love
is putting someone else's needs before
yours like when Kristoff brought you
back into Hans and left you
forever Kristoff loves me wow you really
don't know anything about love do you
say is it getting hot in here here or
what Olaf you're starting to
melt some people are worth melting
for just maybe not right this
second come on Anna let's go find
Kristoff
[Music]
it's getting colder by the minute if we
don't do something soon we all fre to
dead Prince
H Princess Anna is
dead at least we got to say our marriage
vows before she died in my
arms she was killed by Queen Elsa there
can be no doubt about it now we outside
a monster and we are all in great danger
she has been captured and she's in the
Royal dungeon
pre Arendelle looks to
you with a heavy heart I charge Queen
Elsa of Arendelle with treason and I
sentenced her to death prons Queen
Elsa's escaped
[Music]
the we're not going back Spen she's with
her true love now look it's
Krist Elsa Stop you can't run from this
just take care of my sister your sister
returned from the mountain weak and cold
she said you froze her heart what
no Spen look we have to make sure Anna's
all
right he's coming back I guess I was
wrong I guess he doesn't love you enough
to leave you behind forever
Anna I tried to save her but it was too
late your sister is dead because of you
oh
no kof you came
[Music]
backa
no
Anna no no please
Anna
[Music]
Anna I'm so
sorry
[Music]
Han you sacrificed yourself for me of
course said I love
you an act of true love will fall a
frozen
heart love will
thought
love of
[Applause]
[Music]
course
he
I knew you could do it I couldn't have
not without
you hands down this is the best day in
my
life and quite possibly the last oh hold
on hang on little
guy hey it's my own personal
flurry as for you I got this is I don't
understand she froze your heart the only
Frozen Heart around here is yours
oh guard take Prince Hans back to his
country let's see what his 12 Big
Brothers think of his behavior I
couldn't agree with you m majesty and
take the Duke with you aidel will
henceforth and forever no longer do
business of any sort with weaseltown
whistl tap it's whistl tape wristle tap
um I was wondering if if maybe we
couldn't use a royal ice master and
deliverer of course what do you think
Kristof is that a thing it is now you
mean it oh Anna I could kiss you I mean
I could I mean I'd like to may I we me
may we wait
what we
may and one more
thing henceforth the gates will never be
closed
again say
goodbye the pain
of you don't have to feel
[Music]
it love is an
open
lo
lo open with you with you with you with
you with
you open with you with you
you
[Applause]
a
to the pain of
the we
don't open door with you with you with
you with you
[Applause]
Pro