[Music]
little man home
Sam did roll but wasn't expecting the
ball Hidalgo now 4v1 in transition kicks
to the rack for two
[Applause]
he's running in numbers every single
time
[Music]
bye-bye
[Applause]
five for the offensive boards Canada win
it French 24
ball that they win wow give me shooting
it early it was questionable but she
makes it a nobody will question that
Delaney give from way downtown
[Music]
[Applause]
she drives draws the contact on the
blocking foul
[Music]
but man let's see what coach has drawn
up here rejects the screen gray star
McMahon water finish through all the
contact time I've called again that was
superb coach Jody Taylor knows what
she's doing
[Music]