[Music]
I want to pet
goats it lights me like a second
[Music]
again
this just
happened this just
[Music]
happened
oh that feels
[Music]
good
come on come on
joies come on
joies
[Laughter]
[Music]
fall
fore
for
[Applause]
ay
[Music]
[Applause]
ti ti ti
[Music]
thank
you
Atari thanks okay thanks yeah thanks
thank
you I got to get food now all that
night what what can I do for you but
what I'm trying to help
you you guys are
hungry yeah
okay hi little
kitty
hello
[Music]
what that
yeah
jumbo the baby elephants how old are
they you guys got to get off the road
come on come on you got to get off the
road where's your mama
you got get up come on guys where's your
mama oh my
God
sit
down good
[Music]
turn
not that he's going to be one but I'm
videoing to want to help oh thank you he
started kicking around like I
got need to jump a little higher
you can do it Penguin
Jump there you
go there you
go I got a penguin standing on my
belly what are you
doing
little
hey what are you doing you
goober it's not food I don't have food
in
there nope don't Le food
either oh too you're crazy you're crazy
baby
I'm going with it I'm going with it oh
[Music]
yeah
all right all right
relax
relax me
[Music]
when
he
[Music]
oh my
God
he
[Music]
what
right behind
you
[Music]
a
just to
switch
God oh that's my scarf yeah you're
eating it no
no
watch me come on
pleas
[Applause]
again love he's enjoying this he's 24
kilos
he
heavy miss you can try with the other
one he's
ler wa
[Music]
Yoo
w
[Music]
I I I
w
[Music]
[Applause]
ohow
what
hi it's
[Music]
recording
Hey where's my fan
club hi
hi okay you have to go back with your
[Music]
mama
are you
to oh you're angry you don't like your
Christmas
sweater
[Music]
W girl
[Laughter]
[Applause]
my
is that
me I just gave him his first bully
stick he is really not sure what to do
with it he keeps rolling on it that it's
a dead
animal I mean
technically technically it
is he's so funny
lay down lay
down like I
tell lay down lay
down like
[Music]
you you get that peanut
butter
[Laughter]
[Music]
look
he
[Music]
is
oh
[Music]
he
much
[Music]
oh here comes
Gumby
[Music]
for
Fore is
[Music]
he
you were missing some
funny quick they don't F my nose
[Music]
quick
you no buite
it
and
for
spee
for the
treets when the wind blows the cradle
will rock when the bell breaks the
cradle will fall down like a baby
cradles and
[Music]
all
he
[Music]
a
yeah baby got you uhoh got you
oh I got
you oh yeah I got
[Music]
you
n
[Music]
w
come
[Music]
on you hope not oh no oh no come on M me
come
[Music]
on
big guy right
here he just kind of like a little he
Lov the
attention yeah he's got
lot over there so actually I bit oh
[Music]
he
[Applause]
[Music]
I
h
[Music]