[Music]
pour toner onto a cotton pad and apply
all over for smooth hydrated and glowy
skin apply a dropper full of advanced
genifique face serum to the palm of your
hands massage and press into skin with
fingertips for a boost of Radiance
hydration and anti-aging benefits
moisturize with renergie lift
multi-action Ultra face cream for a
tightening Lifting and Firming effect
apply Advanced genifique Eye cream by
dotting under eye using your ring finger
or finger with the lightest touch to
instantly smooth fine lines and wrinkles
pop blushing Tresor shade on cheeks up
to temples and Center Bridge of nose
with full face brush number five for a
touch of highlight sweep rose gold shade
to cheekbones using Contour brush number
seven or fingertips
to Define crease applied shade ladies
night with all over a shadow brush
number 10.
apply dressy Brown shade to lids
apply dressy beige shade to Inner Eye
Corners to brighten eye look
line and Define upper lash line with the
shade brune adore
to complete the sultry eye look apply
lashi doll mascara for lifted lengthened
lashes
to balance out the smokey eye apply a
neutral lip like lapsulu gloss and
Atelier Parisian 213.
finish with the Via Bell fragrance to
experience joyous femininity through
this energizing perfume
[Music]
when it's time to take it all off shake
to activate bifacil eye makeup remover
pour onto a cotton pad until fully
saturated and remove even the most
stubborn makeup repeat as needed
lancome's Beauty Box is loaded with
eight full-size products all wrapped up
in a sustainable golden case made of a
hundred percent recycled materials