a mass of solid ice three times as big
as New York City and it's on the move
for the first time in decades this team
of scientists saw it up close this month
sailing straight through this Mist
knowing that there's an iceberg only a
mile away but not quite seeing it yet
and then suddenly just seeing this
expansive white wool on the horizon
Laura Taylor took water samples near the
iceberg to better understand how they
affect ocean life we saw orcas and birds
and things like that which wouldn't
normally be that populace in that area
of the water and yeah they were all kind
of gathered around the iceberg which
also made it really interesting known as
a23a it broke away from the Antarctic
Coastline in
1986 but quickly became stuck on the
ocean floor now it's moving again North
possibly posing a problem for South
Georgia island east of South America it
could potentially block uh penguin
colonies if it if it comes Nearshore um
and uh disrupts Wild life in that regard
while a23a broke off as a result of its
natural life cycle similar events are
expected to become more common as the
world warms we're going to be seeing
more and more of these ice shelves
breaking away and causing icebergs the
size of of this one and many smaller
ones as well scientists are studying ice
shelves closely because they play a
crucial role they keep the glaciers from
flowing out onto the ice out from the
land and onto the ocean and so that
uncorking of the bottle will allow ice
to move from the land and into the water
and that will create a sea level rise
researchers are trying to better
understand the physics of how all this
happens and what it means for the future
as the climate changes Ben shingler CBC
News Montreal