hey guys hey hey all right here's the
ring
yes yes a thousand times yes
so uh any ideas for the bachelor party
yet
before you start handing out wedding
rings and playing in Bachelor parties
don't you have to decide who your best
man's gonna be
oh it's awkward it's awkward it's
awkward
I sort of already asked Chandler
what he got to do it at your first
wedding Joey I figured you'd understand
I mean I've known him a lot longer come
on Ross look I don't have any brothers
I'm never gonna get to be a best man you
can be the best man when I get married
I'm never gonna get to be your best man
wait so you get to be my best man twice
and I don't get to be yours at all
oh no you yeah of course you can be my
best man
for science fiction writers
I can't believe you're not picking me
hey how could it not be me I'm not even
I don't even all right you know what
that's it from now on Joey I want you to
be my best man yes Shame about you
though
[Applause]
[Music]