[Music]
2024 will feature a variety of exciting
astronomy events we start with a
planetary alignment of Jupiter Mars and
Saturn at number five this alignment on
June 29th will be joined by the moon and
the Eastern Sky Before Sunrise watch as
these worlds form a straight line across
the night sky at number four we have the
super Harvest Moon eclipse
a partial lunar eclipse will be visible
in the United States during a super moon
on September 17th it is the Harvest Moon
because it is the full moon closest to
the Equinox on September 22nd get ready
for planetary oppositions at number
three catch our Celestial Lord of the
Rings Saturn at opposition on September
8th and massive Jupiter will dominate
the night's sky on December 7th a
telescope will help you observe Saturn's
rings and and Jupiter's Great Red Spot
shooting stars will rain down from the
summer night sky with the perced meteor
shower at number two it is one of the
most popular meteor showers boasting 40
to 60 meteors hour catch the shower
after midnight when the moon sets and at
number one the total solar eclipse will
return to the United States on April 8th
the path of totality will travel from
Texas to Maine people in parts of Mexico
and Canada will also the total eclipse
it is by far the number one astronomy
event to mark on your calendar reporting
for ACU weather I'm Justin
pic