now let's return to those events in
Downing Street that we showed you about
an hour or so ago because uh President
Obama or former president Obama there at
number 10 in the last hour he's just
emerged in the last couple of minutes
just want to show you those pictures it
wasn't the longest of meetings perhaps
about 30 40 minutes but there President
Obama just trying to find his car
initially but uh as he wanders over let
me just put the sound up and here just a
little of what the report few few
moments did you discuss
Gaza come and have a CH with us for a
minute how did it go what did you talk
about well he's finally found the car
and avoiding all of those questions uh
we were talking to Helen cat a little
earlier and certain amount of surprise
amongst the political reporters there
suddenly seeing the former American
president arriving there at Downing
Street but no word about what exactly
was discussed in that meeting if we hear
we'll obviously return to that