Ronnie you apologized for how you played
against Barry Hawkins there was
absolutely no need to apologize this
afternoon wasn't that
magnificent
um yeah well um I just I just heard what
Steve Davis said he said like he said I
shouldn't try and entertain the crowd
but I I never have tried to entertain
the crowd I've just always tried to go
out there and play snooker the way I
know I can and if the crowd enjoyed that
then
um but that's never been my sort of
philosophy you know I just like to play
the game well and if I don't play it
well then I get quite frustrated but the
start of the match was uh it wasn't you
know there a few mistakes but then I got
a you know I cleaned it up a little bit
you know um and I need to do that these
days because I can't pot as well as
these guys but I can I can make good
breaks amongst the balls and you know um
make up for it that way so um yeah I I
play listen I won the
match you certainly did and now an
opportunity to become the oldest as well
as the youngest winner of the Masters
just as you did at the UK last month
yeah I don't feel that old I mean I feel
I feel I know my ages but I feel young
in my mind I feel young when I'm around
the table I feel a lot younger to around
the table than I do when I'm playing
these young players right they look old
the way they you know their brains are
quite slow so for me um I still feel
like my brain's pretty quick around a
snooker tail which is which is enough
you know so um yeah they need to get
their act together cuz I'm going blind I
got a dodg arm and bad
knees they still can't beat me you've
still got it ladies and gentlemen you'll
see the rocket tomorrow in the
final hi I'm mon Sullivan and welcome to
euros Sports snooker on YouTube click
here to subscribe to euros Sports
snooker