watch this if you finally want to get Le
you want to be able to go from 30% body
fat to 10% body fat without a struggle I
will take you through that entire
process in this entire video showing you
the scientific evidence behind what
we're going to be doing and what you
need to do step by step these are the
same steps that I've done not only
myself over the last 10 years repeating
this process and improving it using the
research data and all the knowledge I
have as a medical doctor but the same
steps that I've used with all of my
clients that I care deeply about because
they've invested in me but I want to
share that with you finally so the first
thing is going to be contrary to what
you've been told online what you get
online is it's a caloric deficit you
need to do this particular diet it's
keto and it's all lies to an extent let
me make a point I highly recommend you
watch the video till the end because if
you cannot it's a good indication that
you're maybe not prepared to finally get
me but with that being said let's not
waste any time the number one thing I
see with everybody who who never gets
lean or who never finally gets to a
place where they can be lean the rest of
their life is number one is here in the
mind and it's the mindset and before I
get woo woo think about everything and
every little decision you've ever made
that was good for you you had to make a
decision in your mind so what I see with
a lot of the people who've ever
considered working with me or the people
who asked me advice or the people I've
spoken to over the last 10 years about
Dr Mike what do I need to get into shape
it's their mindset number one there's
two things that play a massive role and
and they're very related and once you do
this exercise you'll finally know what
you need to do to finally get Le and
that two things are pain and priority
and I'm going to use the analogy here of
someone with a broken hand someone who
has a broken hand when it's broken they
have pain the most the highest level of
pain and they want to fix this pain
immediately and you need to ask yourself
with your physique and finally get lean
how much pain are you in do you need to
find a a wife or a girlfriend right now
and you need to First lose this weight
do you need to save your marriage is it
extremely important to lose this weight
because there is a health risk and maybe
time is running against you that is what
I call the highest amount of pain and
someone who doesn't have too much pain
or no pain at all is someone who's maybe
they were playing a bit of tennis and
their elbow hurts they don't even
consider going to the doctor but someone
with a high amount of pain has to see
someone immediately and with that comes
priority depending on how much pain you
have will determine how much priority it
is so for most of you if you're watching
this video ask yourself where does this
between I have my hand broken and I'm
just so fat I it's the number one goal I
have in my life it's my health and
fitness and you know what it's okay I
need to focus on my family right now I
need to focus on my business or I need
to focus on something else right that's
going to consume time maybe you have a
newborn when you finally realize where
you are in the Spectrum and if you're at
a high amount of pain that's the number
one thing in your priority list it's the
number one thing is your health and
fitness those people are the ones who
get the best results and those those
typically are my clients because they
will listen to everything I say and they
will also cut out all the excuses that
people usually have which is I don't
have time this is too much it's too
difficult usually people who really want
something are ready to do whatever it
takes in the right manner so ask
yourself write in a list what's a
priority in your life in general do this
exercise and do it right now if you
cannot even do that exercise click out
goodbye I'll see you in the next video
but if you can write in your list hey
what's the most important maybe it's
your family and you need to ask okay
what's more important right now maybe is
it making money and your work or is it
your health if it's your health if your
health falls in the first or second
priority in terms of work your family
and everything else going on in your
life maybe you're a student maybe you
need to pass so maybe your family's
maybe spending time with your family's
number one getting good grades in
universities number two maybe finding a
girlfriend is number three and getting
in shape is number four don't waste your
time that's what happens with a lot of
people and then they fail and they start
eating terribly because they get so
upset because they don't see the weight
scale go down and they end up getting
more weight so figure out where this
Falls in your priority finally after you
figured out okay Mike it is in my top
two step one is done you've come to the
mindset that this is important to you
when you need to make a difference the
second thing you need to interpret
mindset wise is how much time are you
going to give yourself those who decide
to give themselves 1 month typically go
for surgery liposuction gastric bypass
balloon maybe a zemp the people who
decide that they want to give themselves
2 months to get into shape are the
people who end up doing things that
aren't sustainable the keto diet juice
cleansing water fast herbal life
challenges and typically those people
who give themselves 2 months and 1 month
those people typically fail and CU
they're in so much pain they end up
trying new things which I totally get
that's life you know you try things you
fail you try again so there's no problem
with that but the people who decide to
give themselves 3 months 4 months 5
months who give their body Grace and
understand it will take time to be able
to get into the goal the shape of my
life because it took time for me to gain
the weight it didn't happen overnight
those are the people that will see most
success because they're patient and they
will continuously practice the correct
habits necessary so that they can
finally get lead and this is what I mean
by mindset and psychology figure out
your priority all right and then finally
figure out how much time you're willing
to dedicate if it's in your top two of
your priority list you're luck if it's
three let's say it's maybe third right
maybe let's say it's third I'm not even
going to give you going to give you
example if it's third in your list then
all you need to do is just give yourself
more time this way you won't be
frustrated and you won't give up too
soon so it is pain and priority and the
second thing is time now that we've
established this you're willing to give
yourself 3 months to 4 months you're
willing to dedicate your life to being
able to get into great shape because you
know it's a life-changing experience I
call getting in shape being pre-written
and I don't mean only rich in wealth I
mean rich in who you can be as a human
being rich in the value you can give to
your family because now you know how to
get into shape you can get everyone in
your family in shape as well and
research has shown this if someone in
your family gets in shape the chances
that everyone else around you gets in
shape is so much higher raise the
standard for yourself financially and
for your family now that that's out of
the way Come with me now let's figure
out how to really establish a caloric
deficit I'm going to use a client in
mine his name is Gary and I'm going to
use the exact metrics he gave me when he
started with me this won't be the exact
way I build someone's caloric deficit in
their diet and I'm going to show you the
logic so you can literally copy what I'm
doing here and do it for yourself so you
can get rid of your belly fat and
finally get
neat okay so let's figure out what you
need to do to finally be able to get
lean what you need to do and I'm telling
you don't try and do something different
compared to what I'm doing literally
copy exactly what I do and I'll explain
why right so I want you to open your
laptop and I'm going to put these links
in the description of the video now the
resources we're going to use we're going
to use my website scys science.com we're
also going to use Ai and we're finally
also going to use another calculator all
of these are free now to give you the
details of the person I'm going to use
and you can make the exact same I'm
going to use a client of mine called
Gary Gary's male he's 45 years old he
196.7 lb which is equivalent to 89.2 2
kg he's 511 which is 180 cm and he has
decided he's going to train five times
in the week all we need to do and that's
the info you need your gender your age
weight height and how many times you're
going to train I'm going to input this
details in here so 45 his height 180 cm
and he's male and in kilog his weight is
going to be 89.2
89.2 and as you can see this BMR
calculator
is calculating how many calories his
body Burns at rest right because again
we need to get this number for if I just
laid on a bed the entire day how many
calories will my body burn and this will
change based off of how tall you are how
much you weigh in your gender so we're
also going to factor in his activity
what type of movement is he doing right
how much okay we now figured out how
much his body is doing when it's doing
nothing let's have a general estimation
of how much he's doing when he's moving
around and exercising and the easiest
way we do this is by determining how
many workouts you're going to do per
week because Gary is training five times
in the week I consider this person to be
active right so I'm going to put him at
that now the BMR calculator here on my
website has given him
2785 so I'm going to copy that and I'm
going to put that here in a note you
guys are seeing my screen here I'm going
to put your s SPS and that is his
maintenance so then let's go to chat
let's go to the AI and I'm literally
going to just copy the details and I'm
going to paste it here I'm going to
say you are an expert health and
fitness
coach give me the
total
daily energy expenditure for the
following
information right and I'm just going to
paste that that note and literally just
write the exact same thing but with your
own details right and I'm going to press
enter so the AI has given Gary
2,787 so we're just going to put that
here
2,787 and as you can see they are
roughly the same and again all these
numbers are in theory they're all using
the same equation to calculate this
right and I'm not even going to go into
the detail cuz all you need to do is
click on the links and save yourself the
time now we know how many calories Gary
needs to eat to maintain his weight
right so his maintenance calories is on
average right and what I like to do and
this is my logic I like to round it off
and I'm just going to simplify it so my
calculator said
2785 the calculator.net said
2790 the AI said
2782 all I'm going to do to simplify it
and it's not going to make a big
difference is I'll just round it off to
2,800 so to make it easier for you just
round it off now we know what his
maintenance calories is that is the
amount of food and calories you can eat
every day to maintain the weight that he
currently has but we don't want that we
want to lose fat now this is 5 lbs of
fat this is 5 lbs of muscle just to give
you guys a estimation let's assume this
is a pound of fat to lose a pound of
research has shown if I were to take a
fire just in basic terms and burn it all
to lose a pound of fat if I want it to
disappear it's 3,500 calories and to
lose a pound in a week we need to be in
a caloric deficit of 3,500 calories a
week and the simple way we can do that
is saying 3,500 divided by 7 days in the
week which will give us 500 so simply we
will do
2,800 Min - 500 and that should put us
in a caloric deficit to lose one pound
of fat a week and I only want you to
have the objective of losing one pound
of fat a week like I said once you've
agreed that you want to give your body
time this is the easiest way to go about
it if you're a professional like myself
then you can do more and you know the
effects of doing more but now we
understand okay I'm going to be in a
caloric deficit of 500 right so
2800 minus 500 is going to give us
2,300 so now we've done the biggest
thing we understand how many many
calories I need to eat every day so I
can lose a pound of fat per week but
let's say a pound of weight now the next
places like Mike okay I now know how
many calories I need to eat to lose
weight what about the macros the macros
and why this is important the protein
carbs and fats those three things all
have its function protein to build
muscle carbs for energy and fat for
hormonal regulation now we want to get
the perfect amount and you want to do
this scientifically the way I would so
the very easy way and I say this for 90%
of you is to give yourself 1 g of
protein per pound of body weight
considering you don't have any kidney
issues or liver issues if you're a
healthy male or female then please just
follow one G per pound of body weight
with that being said now we can
calculate our macro so Gary's
196.7 lb right so technically I should
give Gary
196.7 g of protein but again I want to
make this easy so so from my experience
and it's not going to make a big
difference what makes a big difference
is that you follow the plan I'm going to
give Gary 200 100 g of protein I am just
rounding that off what we're going to
need to figure out the rest we do want
to know how many calories there are so
just for General reference guys if you
don't know maybe you do maybe you're a
genius 1 g of protein is equal to 4
calories 1 G of carbs is equal to 4
calories 1 G of fat is equal to 9 so now
I know that I'm going to give give
myself 200 g of protein and to figure
out how much that is in calories is
going to be 200 multiplied by 4 the
total calories that's going towards my
protein in my diet is going to be 2 800
calories right so I'm just going to
write that down so now we figured out
the protein now you say okay cool what's
the next thing we figure out we need to
figure out how many grams of fats we're
going to eat now the easy way to do this
and now when I work with someone I try
and determine like what foods they enjoy
some people like more fattier Foods some
people like Less fattier Foods and they
prefer carbs at the very low end do not
go lower than this please just give
yourself 20% of your total calories
towards carbs which is just some simple
mathematics we determined 2300 is how
many calories I'm going to eat and I
want to eat 20% of that right which is2
multiply that by 02 and that's going to
give you 460 calories right that's how
much is going to go towards fats and
we're going to just put that here we
also want to know okay how many grams of
fat is that Mike well we know that 1 G
of fat is equal to 9 calories so to
figure this out we're going to do 460 /
by 9 so divide it by 9 and that is going
to give us
51.1 repeated right so what I'm going to
do to make it easy I am just going to
say 50 g again I'm just trying to make
this easy 50 51 it's really not going to
make a difference if you like measure
that it's you can't even see it in olive
oil so little but that's just how I make
it easy so I'm just going to say I'm
going to give myself 50 g so to figure
out how many calories that is I'm going
to say 50 multiplied by multiplied by 9
right to figure out how many total
calories so 450 is going to go towards
fats so
450 okay Mike how do I determine how
much carbs I'm eating and this is where
people get it wildly inaccurate they're
like it's too much carbs I'm I'm afraid
you're just traumatized because you
don't have good habits carbs are good
for you especially if you're eating it
at the correct amount your brain
utilizes carbohydrates imagine every
time you're undereating carbohydrates
severely your brain isn't functioning
optimally every time you're not giving
yourself enough carbohydrates you're not
training strong enough you it makes you
weak it makes you not want to move and
then you wonder why am I not burning
calories you need to move too a caloric
deficit is all about burning more
calories than what you're eating you
could start moving more and burn fat
that way right without getting onto a
rant right we're going to solve for x
now now we're going to figure out the
carbs so we basically give the rest of
our calories towards carbs so we take
2,300 everything we have and then we're
going to minus that by 450 that's the
fats and then if you remember I'm going
to minus that by 800 cuz that's the
total calories that's going towards my
protein which means the rest of my
calories that goes towards carbs is
equivalent to one 1,50 and then I'm
going to divide that by 4 and that's
going to give me
262.50 what I will do I'm just going to
round it off to
263 to make it easy again so 263 that's
the total amount of carbs we're going to
eat
263 right and I'm just going to write
1050 and voila you have your Macros I
figured it out literally copy me 1 g of
protein per pound of body weight 20% of
your total Cal towards your fats and
then finally the rest figure out for X
so you can figure out your carbs now you
guys when you when you figure this out
finally you're like you know what that's
too much carbs I'm going to cut it down
no don't do that it's what the science
said just follow the science I won't
even go into aand but why I say if you
give yourself more time you'll actually
follow a plan and you won't try and do
shortcuts here and there because the
biggest thing I've seen with people
especially who want to work with me is
that they either are eating way too much
or way too little way too much is
they're gaining weight because they're
cheating on the weekend they're binging
Etc and way too little is that their
metabolism adapts to all those little
calories and then they find themselves
in a rock in a hard place and then
they're too fearful of eating a little
bit more cuz it's like online it's being
perpetuated that you need to be in a
caloric deficit and that's all in your
mind I need to eat very little really
just trust the science just trust it if
you finally want to be able to get to
your goal you finally want to reach your
dream body your dream physique you want
to be like my clients Shannon Sandra
Amanda hiy you finally want to work with
someone who's going to guarantee results
then go into the description of my video
and fill out the application I work with
busy professionals who are prepared to
invest in themselves and want a
guaranteed result and that knows that
their health is priority and it knows
that doing this transformation will not
only help them and for you lady that
won't only help you but that's going to
help your entire family cuz you're going
to cook better for your husband you're
going to know exactly what to give to
your kids if that is you you're a busy
mom and you want to get results for you
and your family fill out the application
and I'll jump on a call with you so I
can gather all this data and even more
okay now we've figured out the
complicated stuff now it's putting it
into practice this is what people
struggle with and I'm going to show you
how easy it is I'm going to open my
fitness pal now I'm just going to use my
fitness pal you can use any app you like
there's lose it there's an app by Jeff
nippard it's called macro Factor I've
never used it but I've heard it's good
give that a go it's also paid but
nonetheless but I'm going to use my
fitness pal cuz it's what I've utilized
my entire life so first you're going to
go to more and you're going to go to
goals and you're going to go to calories
and what I'm going to do I'm going to
set the macros that I calculated earlier
so we determined that protein was going
to be at
200 and I'm going to put that here and
we said fats is going to be 50 and I
said that my carbs are going to be 2 63
and that gives us exactly
232 calories and I'm going to check and
that is fine guys like
2,32 don't get so obsessed with the
little little detail just cover the
basics first and I'm going to now show
you how to build a meal plan I'm going
to show you how to build a meal plan and
what you should do and I'm going to take
things out of my fridge I have some of
the stuff here that I took out to just
show you guys but we generally like the
the ideas I have is that at Max I want
about 50 g of protein per meal so if I
have 200 g of protein I maybe want four
meals at least if I'm maybe 150 lb and
I'm eating 150 at least three meals
right so each meal can have 50 g of
protein but I'm going to do this very
simple we are first going to have oats
and you know what I decided I'm going to
have protein oats so I'm going to take
out the ingredients that's going to be
necessary for my protein oats and I'm
going to make protein oats this way so
I'm going to add this protein powder to
the oats I'm going to have my oats here
I'm also going to add milk the next
thing you're going to utilize is a
weight scale because it's very very
important to make sure that you're
tracking everything accurately and what
I recommend for all you lazy people I'm
lazy too just track one day so I'll
track all of this and then I'll eat eat
the same food every day and then when
you get bored you can change it and the
cool thing is let's say you don't want
oats for breakfast but you want to eat
the rest of the meals you can just
delete all the stuff from oats and you
can put something else that will fit so
now let's figure this out so I'm going
to go here to add food and that's a cool
feature on here you have to pay for the
app like invest in your health guys I'm
not I'm I and before anyone comments
about it's not free anymore just invest
in your health Gan bar code and this is
a cool feature that I really love about
my fitness pal you can scan the barcode
and here it says that 100 G of Oats is
370 calories 55 carb 8 fats 14 protein
I'm just going to eat 100 G I'll leave
it at that and now I want to also add
one scoop of protein so I'm just going
to go here I'm going to take my phone
and literally I'm going to show you guys
How I build a plan now again I have a
data database of over a th recipes I've
been doing this for a decade so I'm
showing you the simplest way I'm going
to SC scan the protein and the the oat
said it's going to give me 14 G one
scoop is 27 you know what I think I want
a little bit more protein so I'm going
to go for two scoops Living Dangerously
and as you can see so far it's showing
me that there's 68 g of protein in my
meal already so that's awesome and then
finally what I'm going to do is I will
have milk right I'm going to make my
oats with some
milk and the one this one is low fat so
when you go to your store or in your
household if you use oat milk no problem
if you use almond milk no problem the
more calorie friendly the better right
so here it's 250 Ms uh let's say I'm
just going to change this unit to one
per 1 ml let's say I want about 350 Ms
right and voila meal one done and that's
my protein notes right so that's
breakfast done now it tells me that I
have 119 carbs left 36 fat 123 protein
if you guys remember from a video I made
and this is why my recipe videos are so
good I made some protein tacos which I
really liked so what I'm going to do is
I'll show you like okay I'm going to
make protein tacos so I'm going to do
this low carb wrap and in tacos you need
lean ground beef so I'm going to take
lean ground
beef and then you know what in those
tacos I had tomatoes I had you know some
iceberg lettuce this I had some pickles
that I added in my tacos what else did I
have Mike ah cheese yeah you know what I
had this uh Philadelphia cheese right as
you guys can tell because I obviously
live in a healthy home I already have
like these cool little snacks and stuff
go to your local grocery store and
search for lower calorie light lowfat
high protein options right so these are
the general ingredients so I'm going to
figure out okay I want to make tacos I'm
going to make three tacos so all I'm
going to do is I'm going to go to diary
and go for lunch add food scan
barcode right I'm going to have three
and it says here that one is 45 G right
so I'm going to have three so I'm just
going to put three in here and that's
tracked for the lean ground beef right
and I'm going to show you guys an
example this is where experience comes
in with your lean ground beef I usually
go 97% lean 3% fat you see like here
where I live they don't show you how
lean I just look at how red it is and
you can see there's not much fat streaks
which is usually the lower fat version
and this is from experience but I will
have about 300 G of this but let's say
for my three wraps cuz I want to bit
let's say I'm going to put 300 G right
so I'm going to put um lean ground beef
and you see here cuz there's no barcode
to scan what's cool about my fitness
pile is you can search a food lean
ground beef and you can search and it's
going to give you a variety of options
and you can see that the first one is
very verified it's 180 calories second
one is verified it's 196 calories at 4 o
um they they all range one here is 170
calories that's 92% lean um I'm going to
put lean ground beef and then I'm going
to write 97 right I'll just search for
what they have there and here they have
97% leanr beef and you can see the first
two options 130 130 170 I'm just going
to pick the top option and the point is
as long as you're consistent with the
option you choose no problem because
next week when you've seen the result
you can decide to just reduce the
quantity and you've still created a a
Delta a deficit I'm going to just change
this to Gams cuz I'm used to that and
I'm going to put 300 and 300 G gives me
exactly 63.5 g of protein 10.6 G of fat
and it comes out to a total of
344 calories obviously there's no
carbohydrates and protein so in a in a
beef so I'm just going to check that
this meal comes out so far with
everything I've added it comes out to
686 calories so there's 32 carb 20 fats
86 g of protein I'm happy with that when
it comes to veget veggies they're so low
calorie no point in tracking it so
veggies I generally don't track
especially non-starchy veggies so no
need to do that and then I'm going to
have three of these so I'm going to go
to add food scan
barcode and then record that um let's
see here one one of these is 16.6 um G
so
16.6 16.6 multiplied by 3 gives me 49.8
so I'm going to put
49.8 right and then finally guys when I
make my wrap I like adding some sauce in
there I'm just going to put this one now
you can use any sauce but track your
sauces I'll use one serving of this
right so I'm going to go add food scan
barcode so don't forget to track your
sauces and your oils it's a common
mistake I see people make so I'll maybe
add two servings of this right to be
clear so I'll add two servings of that
so that's going to give me 30 G so what
I do is I'll put it just to show you
guys how to track the sources I'll put
it on the scale I'll turn it on and then
I'll take it I'll spread it on my meal
I'll put it back and I'll see It'll show
me that it's minus you know 10 until I
get to 30 so that's how you do that and
you just tear when you're ready so now
I've made my wrap so I've tracked my
wrap fantastic now in any good plan I
have a always have a serving of
vegetables in a day like any serving if
it's broccoli whatever you decide but I
have a serving of veggies and also have
a serving of fruit so my fruit for today
I'm going to have an apple so I'm going
to track here right I'm just going to
take this off and this apple is 220 G so
I'm going to go in my snacks and I'm
going to say okay Red
Apple and I'm going to search you see
here it shows one medium
um I'm just going to see if it lets me
choose per gram I'm going to go to grams
and this one is exactly 219 right so I'm
going to track
219 and this apple is 129 calories 30.8
carbs point4 fats point6 protein so
let's say see where we are right cuz
this is like a puzzle so now I have my
breakfast I have my lunch I have my
snack now it shows me from my remaining
calories
I have 49 G of carbs 6 G of fat and 28 g
of protein so now I'm like damn what can
I have for dinner basically I need a a
meal that has carbs in it and I need a
meal that has a lot of protein but very
little fats let's see bread let's see
like how much bread I can have here
because bread is going to be my main
carb source for dinner let's say I want
to have a sandwich I can go to dinner so
I'm going to go to scan barcode for my
bread I'm going to click here now you
see it says here that two slices is 32
remember that I had 45 so let me see
what happens if I choose like three
slices right let's say I want three
slices it takes me to 48.3 that's a
little higher I'm going to I'm just
going to say fine let's do that now it
takes me it says that I have 20 g of
protein left I have no more fats so now
you need to ask yourself what has a lot
of protein no fats and no carbs right
that can be tuna so I could maybe make a
toast with tuna that can be egg whites
or if I want I could just have the toast
literally just toast it and maybe put
butter spray on it that's zero calorie
and then I can have a shake what like
one scoop is usually 20 G with water but
you know what to go with my toast I'm
just going to have egg whites on there
scrambled so I'm going to click here on
the dinner and I'm going to click add
food and I'm going to add egg whites I'm
going to search egg whites right and I'm
going to search that and I will take it
from this eggs here right so in one
large egg this is a large egg it's 17
calories so it shows here one large egg
gives me 3.6 g of protein so let me see
how many I need to hit 20 so if I hit
five that gives me 18 okay let me see
what happens if I take six eggs that
gives me 21.6 I'm going to take six egg
whites and voila guys there it is I
planned my day so this is as it's like a
puzzle right so I went over by my carbs
by one my fats I have 2 G of fat left
and then I went over by my protein by 2
G and I'm over by 58 calories I'm happy
with that I'm going to take that to the
bank and voila now you've had your full
meal plan Planned and that's how easy it
is and you can also use egg white
cardens just the same concept copy me go
into your fridge and just track this and
what happens after a week two weeks
three weeks you you learn so much about
the foods you're putting in your body CU
you're tracking it and you're seeing
okay this is how much the chabani yogurt
has you see I took this up but I didn't
use it right so do this every day and
eventually you're going to figure out
which recipes work for you so the metric
people usually use is a weight scale and
I'm going to talk about this bad boy
right here but an app I highly recommend
you guys download is this app here
called happy scale so an app I recommend
you download this called happy scale
this is what it looks like and you click
that now to know okay Mike how do I know
that this is working I want you to go
every day when you wake up then you get
on the scale and you look huh what's my
weight that's my weight
186.65
6 and I want to say for all you guys
there don't get so emotionally attached
to the number it's just your weight is
literally your mass time gravity it's
just data it's just for you to see where
you are it doesn't mean anything because
I
could let's say I drank this whole
bottle right remember my weight was
186.65
right I'm 2 lb higher no you're not fat
it says you drank more water so the
point I want to make is the weight scale
so many things can fluctuate with your
weight so I'm just going to show you
guys hypotheticals right so I'm going to
add entry here I'm going to go to pounds
and I'm just to make this easy I'm just
going to go to April 1st right April
fo okay I'm just going to go to April
1st and my weight was
186.65 I'm 186 flat and then the day
after I go to
185. 6 I'm like amazing man this thing
is working weekend comes it's a Friday
and you decide to have a cheat meal and
you say you see the next day the next
morning you didn't sleep enough you you
know you had a bad meal and you see wow
my weight's back up to 188 terrible ah
sad but then you fast forward the next
day and you get back to the diet you
pick yourself back up and you see okay
I'm back at 185 then you see okay I'm
back at 184 and then you see that you're
back at
183 a whole new low weigh in and if you
look at this graph that I'm showing you
you can see that the graph is trending
downwards right you're seeing although
you had this cheat meal it didn't affect
your weight and that's the one way to
look at it the second thing I recommend
to do every two weeks do tape
measurements right Do shoulders do chest
do midsection belly button do thighs do
glutes and you can use that as a second
way to track to see if it's getting
better and then finally take pictures
you want to take pictures in one
location once a week right let's say
every Sunday front side back and take
them every Sunday and you can use your
weight scale your tape measurement and
the photos to be able to truly see okay
it's working or no it's not working and
then this way you're making a scientific
and smart decision based off of three
different variables and just depending
on this now let's talk about cardio what
to do with cardio follow me we have the
diet part figured out now the next part
is your cardio forget the hit forget all
the different technical cool like cardio
machines keep it simple I just want you
to walk every day I want you to hit
8,000 daily steps and every week
increase it by 500 week one when you
start once you've done the diet walk
8,000 steps if you walk more no problem
but I just want you to walk I don't want
you to run I don't want you to do
anything crazy I just want you to walk
and increase that by 500 each and every
single week we know that 10,000 steps
will roughly help you burn 500 calories
this varies depending on your height and
your weight and your gender but walking
Taps many into fat stores and it will
burn more fat you can go outside and
walk at the park you can walk every you
can walk to the gym you can do different
forms um something I recommend to all my
clients is get an under the desk or a
walking pad so I will watch Netflix on
my TV here when I'm spending time with
my family or after a meal I want to
digest it a bit better I'll walk on a
walking pad that's the only cardio you
want to focus on keep it simple it will
help you lose fat walking is the best
cardio by far cuz you can do it every
day you don't need to go to the gym and
research is shown that will tap M need
to fast St and also it's not as
intensive on your body so
on Monday Wednesday Friday right now
that's just an example let's say you say
hey Mike I can only train four times in
a week the best split for that is an
upper body lower body upper body lower
body the best let's say you train five
times in a week you can go upper body
lower body Push Pull legs push means all
your push muscles chest shoulders
triceps pull means all the pulling
exercises back biceps and then legs
obviously quads hams glutes and that's
five times in the week you can also do
full body five times in the week that's
another option there's many different
options but those are the two and then
finally if you want to train six times
in a week you can go push pull legs and
repeat Push Pull legs right and you want
to train with a good form watch me do my
form here you want to train with
intensity you want to choose the
heaviest weight you can and you want to
do that consistently each and every
single week this will help you build
your muscle and it's that simple don't
complicated good form and then make sure
you're hitting the gym and then finally
guys the way I like describing sleep
your body is a Ferrari it is the most
well-designed organism on this Earth and
sleep is the equivalent to the oil in
your Ferrari if you don't get enough
sleep if you don't put enough oil in
that engine of your Ferrari it's not
going to make it down the road it's
going to break down so when you're
sleeping more you're allowing yourself
to have optimal levels of testosterone
you're going to have good hormonal
balance you're going to have good
recovery from the damage you've done to
your muscle your muscle repairs itself
when you're sleeping you're allowed to
think faster think better it fixes
everything I've had clients who I just
focus on their sleep in the beginning
they're maybe sleeping 6 hours and I got
them to 7 to 8 and the weight started
flying off because there's so many
implications that sleep has so if you're
sleeping little and you're trying
everything that's probably the reason
why you're not losing weight it will
drop your cortisol levels it will do so
much I could make a Whole 30 40 minute
video just on sleep so at bare minimum
sleep 7 hours if you can sleep more then
sleep more General things set a time to
go to bed stop eating food 4 hours
before bed stop drinking liquids 2 hours
before bed reduce your blue light
exposure so stop looking at screens or
get a blue light blocker 1 hour before
bed and then no caffeine after midday
right cuz you don't want to be drinking
caffeine at 400 p.m. and you're
wondering why your your hot your heart's
going bump bump bump when you when
you're in bed and it's just going like
crazy no caffeine after midday and
you'll be able to sleep I'll leave the
video here I hope it was helpful and if
it was let me know in the comment
section down below and yeah leave it a
gentle thumbs up and share this with a
friend they need it
peace