the dotom bubble started around 1997
peaked in 2000 and ultimately bursted by
2002 as the name suggests the bubble
revolved around speculative investments
in internet companies simply put
investors were so excited about the
progress of the internet that they
invested in pretty much any tech company
with a pulse they stopped caring about
whether or not a company was profitable
or at least could eventually become
profitable Common Sense became a Rarity
from 1997 to March 2000 prices went up
about five times only to go down five
times and return to their pre-boom
levels from 2000 to 2002 a drop which
was also exacerbated by the terrorist
attacks of September 11th 2001 only one
out of two internet companies survived
with businesses such as pets.com going
from a market capitalization of over
$300 million to zero within just 268
days there are however also success
stories such as Amazon which went from
around $100 during the bubble Peak all
the way down to $7 after it burst but
then climbed back up to over $600 per
share the conclusion is simple like any
other Mania theom bubble is a
fascinating human nature lesson